"To the end of horizon,”
天之涯
“four corners of Earth,”
地之角
“A bottle of wine for remaining joy,”
一壶浊酒尽余欢
as sun sets among the mountains.
夕阳山外山
Brilliant...
好 好
Counselor! You prefer the food or my singing?
汤师苑 是好吃 还是好听
llove them both! Outstanding!
也好听 也好吃 都好 都好
"Brain and brawn have helped me far,”
我马某走南疤北
that's why lam so unique!
靠的就是能文能武 与众不同
One must learn to live in style!
不光吃喝玩乐 更要雪月风花
"Governor, with your style and poise,”
马县长此番风度
you remind me of...
正好比…
a modern-day Robin Hood!
大风起兮云飞扬
Bullshit!
屁
Robin Hood is a common thief!
刘邦是个小人
with Samson's might and Solomon's wisdom!
力拔山兮气盖世
"Bullshit! - Yes, bullshit!"
屁 屁屁
"Counselor, if you're trying to flatter me,”
汤师爷 你要是拍我马屁
you must first woo my wife!
就先要先过夫人这一关
Compose a poem in her honour.
写首诗 写首诗
"It must have a tempest, food,”
要有风 要有肉
"a hotpot, some mist,”
要有火锅 要有雾
“pretty maidens, and a mule!”
要有美女 要有了驴
"Let's eat, sing and be merry!”
一起吃 一起唱
"Sir, we are the elite Republican Guards,”
报告县长 我们铁血十八星陆军
here to ensure your safe passage!
护送县长安全上任
We -
我们…
clon't - need - to - eat!
不吃饭
You missed?
没打中
Let the bullets fly...
让子弹飞一会儿
Two and Three come with me.
老二老三跟我走
The rest round up the horses.
其他人把白马抓回来
Raining hot pot?
火锅
"Pop, we've looked all over.”
欧 全都找遍了
There is absolutely nothing!
没钱 没货 也没有银子
Should we just kill the two survivors?
人倒是剩两活的 杀不杀
Tell me where the money is?
钱藏在哪儿了 说出来
"Or I'll cut off your head,”
闹钟响之前要是说不出来
when the alarm goes off.
脑袋搬家
Stop it!
oa
Tears won't stop it from ticking.
哭也算时间啊
You'd better come clean with them.
有什么就说什么嘛
"Who might you be, ma'am?”
这位夫人 你是谁
I'm the Governor's wife.
我就是县长夫人啊
Forgive my impudence.
失敬 失敬
So you must be the Governor.
那你就是县太和分
"Yes, of course! There's money!”
有钱 有钱…
We're on our way to inauguration.
我跟县长进城上任
He ruined it all by getting drowned!
县长济死了 现在没有
But we can still hit jackpot
上任就有 上任就有钱
if we take his vacant post.
上任就有
lll give you another chance. Tell me more.
再给你一圈 顺着买官往下说
"$200,000..."
有二十万
Where is it?
钱呢
Bought the post with it.
买官了
What for?
买官干什么
To make more money.
赚钱
How much?
能赚多少
Twice as much.
一信
How long will it take?
多长时间
Ayear.
一年
I've to wait one year?
我要等你一年
“A month, if you're in luck.”
半年… 手气好 一个月也行
Who will be the governor?
县长淹死了 谁去上任
Me.
我
And who might you be?
你是谁
I'm a counselor.
师爷
You dare to impersonate the Governor?
你一个师爷敢冒充县长
They've never met him.
没人认识县长长什么模样
Done this before?
你干过几次
Twice a year.
一年两次
Since when?
于过几年
Eight years ago.
八年
You've made more than $6.4 million?
八八六十四 你赚过六百四十万
"That's what the ""Governor'™ made.”
他 他县长赚过六百四十万
l only get the small change.
我不是师爷么 我就赚个零头
Ever failed?
没失过手
"We use our brains, not brawn.”
不动手 拼的是脑子 不流血
Where are you heading to?
你这次去娜儿 上任
Goose Town.
忽城
How do you explain the hold-up and the bodies?
火车被劫 你的人淹死了 怎么交代
l bought the train and hired the soldiers.
车是我买的 人是我雇的 没人追查
No one will ever find out.
没有人追查
Don't take it off! Leave your mask on!
别摘 别摘… 千万别摘
I know the rules.
规矩我懂
No one lives after seeing a bandit's face.
看见你的脸我就活不成
Just wait here for me.
你把我放了 我上任忽城
lll bring you the money once I have it.
琶了钱 都给你 都给你
"We came to rob a train,”
弟兄们动回道
we can't go empty-handed.
一分钱都没捞着 不合适吧
"No, you can't.”
不合适
If you die for peeking at me...
你看了我一眼小命就委了 也不合适吧
That's even worse.
更不合适
Can I borrow those bodies?
你那些济死的兄弟借我用用
Yes. These bullies deserve no better.
用 …他们欺男霸女 死有余训
But what do you want to do with them?
不是 死了有什么用啊
They can be more useful than the living.
死人有时候比活人有用
Take a look at me.
师爷 睁开眼看我一眼 不
Look at me!
看一眼 不不
Just one look!
就看一眼 不不
What's your name?
师爷贵姓
he.
免贵(别客气)
What's your bloody name?
姓什么
Tang.
姓汤
"Tll be the Governor,”
汤师爷 我当县长
and you'll be my counselor!
你继续当我的师爷
Let's go and rule Goose Town.
咱们忽城走一趟
"Ma'am, coming with us?”
夫人 要不要走一趟
"Well, why not?”
走就走嘛
"Brothers, let's move on to Goose Town!"
弟兄们上任忽城
Goose Town here we come!
上任牧城
We've messed up badly.
兄弟们失了手
End up drowning your husband.
让你丈夫横遭了不测
feel bad about it.
我很是愧商
I've already been widowed four times.
我已经第四次当寡妇了
"Don't let there be a fifth time, then!"
那可千万别第五次路
That's all up to you.
那就要看你的本事了
What's important for a couple?
师爷 当夫妻最要紧的是什么
In love.
恩爱
I can't hear you.
听不见 再说一遍
"Six, come greet your Mom.”
来 见过母亲大人
"wish you well, Mother.”
母亲大人好 小六子有礼了
You bring your son to battles?
你出生入死 还带着儿子啊
His father was a comrade. Died in battle.
他驳是我的兄弟 阵亡了
Sol adopted him as my god son.
所以他就成了我的儿子
Now you're my mother.
所以呢 你现在就是我的母亲大人
"After we're done with Goose Town,”
等这桩买卖做完后
you must come and join our gang.
跟我们一块回山里吧
Then you can continue to play mother.
你可以继续当我的母亲
One should always aim high.
人往高处走 水往低处流
“After serving as county governor,”
当惯了县长
I can't return to banditry.
再回去当麻菲
I won't be able to handle it.
恐怕会有点不习惯吧
Once you've scaled Mount Everest...
曾经沧海难为水嘛
Such eloquence!
说得好
Then what should we do?
那怎么办啊
We can continue to be civil servants!
怎么办 继续当官鹃
"Use your brain, not brawn.”
遇事要多动脑筋
Think twice before you make a move.
先动脑子后动手 明白吗
Got it.
明白
Counselor!
师爷
We're government officials now.
我们现在是做官的人了
We can't act like bandits!
不得再有匪气
What is a good governor's virtue?
师爷 当县长最要紧的是什么
You've escaped once.
你逃过一次
Try this one more time...
你要是再敢要我.…
You'll have me beheaded!
明白 脑袋搬家
Let's gol!
进城
City girls are so fair and delicate!
城里的女人就是白啊
"Pop, look!”
欧 你看
Look what they've mace of you!
他们怎么把你画成这样了
"The less it resembles me, the safer lam!"
越不像越安全
"Welcome, your honour!"
恭迎县长大人
Appointment Warrant!
委任状
Ma Bangde is appointed Goose Town Governor
兹委任马邦德为忽县县长
“by authority of the Provincial Chairman,”
此状 中华民国萨南康省主席巴青泰
“on this 28th day of February, the 8th year of the Republic...”
中华民国八年八月二十八日
Master Huang has arrived!
黄老爷驾到
Greetings to Master Huang!
黄老爷吉祥
Huang Silang is the local godfather.
此万南国一霸黄四郎
Made his fortune from opium and human trafficking.
于的是贩卖人口 倒卖烟土的大生意
Master is currently engaged.
黄老爷百忙无眼
"So he sends his majordomo, Hu Wan!"
特命我黄府大管家胡万
"And his militia coach, Wu Zhichong!"
黄府团练教头武智冲
"To welcome you, sir, with his hat!"
礼帽 礼瑶 欢迎县长
Who dares win!
来者不善啊
Do you dare?
你才是来者
"He's here, sir.”
老爷 来了
Who's here?
谁呀
Yourself!
你自己
Long live Master Huang!
黄大和爷万寿
Greetings from Yang Wanlou!
小的杨万楼 这厅有礼
A remarkable fake!
硒品是个好东西
Take a few steps.
走几步
Walk purposefully.
走出个虎虎生风
Purposefully...
走个虎虎生风
Walk with spirit.
走出一个一日千里
Spiritedly...
走个一日千里
Walk pensively.
走出一个忧如隔世
Pensively...
走个忧如隔世
Why isn't she afraid?
你说她怎么不害怕了啊
She must be daft.
有点傻吧
Know why we shot these bandits?
为什么要枪此麻菲
It's because they ambushed the Governor.
因为他们抢官车 动县长
Let this be a lesson to all!
枪此他们 就是为了让大家了明白
Never mess with the Governor!
对抗官府之下场
Hail the Governor!
县长来了 于城太平了
Peace and justice is here!
县长来了 青天就有呼
Great speech!
师爷 说得好啊
Remember what I told you?
你记得我跟你说过
The dead can be really handy.
有了时候死人比活人有用吧
You're absolutely right.
是 死人是比活人有用
Such arrogance!
霸气外露
He's trouble.
找死
A show of force!
刚进城就开枪
This one is a tricky customer!
这不是二八开能打发走的
Should we strike first?
先发制人
No hurry.
不急
Let's toy with him.
跟他要要
"No hurry, let's toy with him!"
不急 跟他要要
Cut it out!
算了吧
Cut it out! Cut it out!
算了算了
Cut it out...
算了吧
Cut it out!
算了
Cut the bloody hell out!
算你妈的吧
Butler!
胡王
Yes sir!
是 老爷
Take him to the dentist.
多拔他几颗牙
Fix him up with gold teeth like mine.
跟我一样 全镶成金的
Yes sir!
电 下
Madam!
夫人
"The reason am here,”
兄弟我此番
“is to get rich,”
只为劫财
hot to get laid.
不为动色
"We share a bed,”
同床
but not our dreams.
但不入身
Here's a pistol.
有枪在此
"Just in case,"
若是兄弟我…
"l overstep my mark,”
有冒犯夫人的举动
shoot me between the eyes.
你可以随时于掉我
"But if you have that urge,”
若是夫人有任何要求
“then yours truly,”
兄弟我…
would be happy to oblige.
也决不推辞
Let's sleep!
睡觉
Husband and wife - even for a day...
一日夫妻百日恩呐
"I've always wanted to be a governor's wife,”
反正呢 我就想当县长夫人
and I don't care who the governor is.
谁是县长 我无所谓
Your guest?
我客气吗
Go ahead!
客气呀
You make me blush!
这还算客气
"Well, do I?”
你太客气哮
Then must oblige.
怎么才能不客气啊
We're late!
晚了
Previous governors
前几任县长
have levied tax for the next 90 years!
把忽城的税 收到九十年以后了
So everyone has paid up to 2010!
也就是西历二零一零年
We've come to the wrong place!
咱们来错地方了
"Llike this town, though.”
我倒是觉得这个地方不错
But people here have nothing left.
百姓成穷抱了 没油水可榨了
I never take from the poor.
老子从来就没想刊穷鬼的钱
"Who are your victims, then?”
不刊穷和鬼的钱你收谁的呀
"The rich, of course.”
谁有钱赚谁的
Ever been a Governor?
当过县长吗
No.
没有
Listen carefully!
我告诉你
"You have to devise ways to raise money,”
县长上任 得巧立名目
"Make the rich pay first,”
拉拢豪绅 缴税捐款
townsfolk will follow suit.
他们交了 才能让百姓跟着交钱
"Then reimburse the rich with what they paid,”
得钱之后 豪绅的钱如数奉还
and split the rest 30-70!
百姓的钱 三七分成
We only get 70?
怎么才七成啊?
"No, the rich get 70.”
七成是人家的
We get 30 at Huang’s discretion.
能得三成还得看黄四郎的脸色
At whose discretion?
谁的脸色
Him.
他
"I come all this way,”
我大老远的来一趟
only to become his running cog?
就是为了看他的脸色
Correct.
对
"It's hard enough robbing your train,”
我好不容易动了趟火车
and play-act governor.
当了县长
“make up silly excuses,”
还得巧立名目
Doesn't that make me a beggar?
我不成跪着要饭的了吗
If you want to put it that way...
那你要这么说
"Many would love to be in your position,”
买官当县长还真就是跪着要饭的
but few could afford to buy a post.
就这 多少人想跪还没这门路呢
Do you know why I became an outlaw?
我问你 我为什么要上山当土匪
It's because my legs are not built for kneeling!
我就是腿脚不方便 跪不下去
“If you want to make money standing tall,”
原来你是想站着赚钱啊
tide back to the mountains.
那还是回山里吧
I don't get this.
这我就不明白了
"Lam now governor,”
我已经当了县长了
how can I be worse off than a bandit?
怎么还不如个土匪呀
You may be a governor to the townsfolk.
百姓眼里 你是县长
"But in the eyes of Huang,”
可是黄四郎眼里
you're a mere beggar!
你就是跪着要饭的
This is only business. There is no shame.
赚钱嘛 生意 不寒酸
The hell there isn't!
寒酸
I's shameful!
很寒酸
"Do you prefer to stand tall,”
那你是想站着
or do you want to make money?
还是想赚钱呢
I want to do both.
我是想站着 还把钱赚了
No way.
了史不成
Can make money with this?
这个能不能赚钱
"Yes, but only as a bandit.”
能赚 山里
"Yes, but only on your knees.”
能赚 跪着
"Combining the two,”
这个加上这个
can l make money standing tall?
能不能站着把钱赚了
"Mr. Nine, who exactly are you?”
敢问九简大哥 何方神圣
"Rocky" Zhang!"
鄙人 张麻子
Stop it! This is not a tree!
那不是树 别砍了
It's an ancient magisterial drum!
这是冤鼓 乾隆那时候设的
"Totally neglected,”
老没人敲就生了根 长了叶
it's taken root and sprouted leaves.
就成现在这样了
"Pop said to me,”
我侈说了
we need this to convene court.
有宫鼓 就说明有视
He wants to try a case.
他说他要判个案
What case?
于儿有客呐
Has someone filed a complaint?
谁敢有冤呐
It's been here for 100 years.
这都一百多年了
“If you now unveil the drum,”
你要把它砍了 把鼓露出来
who knows what case it may bring?
不定出多大客呐
Where's your old man?
别砍啦 你移他人了呢
In bed.
睡觉
At this hour? Who with?
跟谁睡啊 怎么还睡啊
What happened?
鼓呢
Look what you've done!
叫你别砍吧 把鼓给砍跑了
Drum...!
鼓鼓鼓鼓
Out of my way!
躲开
It's homing in on me!
这鼓怎么跟着我呀
Help! Help!
救命呀.… 大人
"My wine is ruined,”
可惜了老子的酒
my mood destroyed!
老子的雅兴全让你给毁了
Everything's spoilt!
全毁了
lll deal with you another clay.
改日我再收拾你
The drum is shattered!
鼓都手破了
So there must be a case to try!
说明你们俩很冤呐
Court!
升堂
How have you been wronged?
客从何来
I'm not.
没锡
"If no one is wronged, case dismissed!"
有客的说视 没冤的那就散 散会
Sir!
冤
Ihave wronged Master Wu.
不是我冤 是武举老爷多
Il was careless.
小的不长眼
[ran into him and knocked over his wine.
在躲鼓的时候 磁酒了武举老爷的酒
Completely ruining his day.
害得武举老仓没有了骨口
I need to kowtow and apologise. Sorry!
小的应该给武举老爷赔礼 赔礼
That was nothing.
老子不罗
How dare you say nothing?
敢说你不冤
Kneel!
跪下
He coaches Huang’s militia. Go easy on him.
这可是黄四郎的团练教头 跪不得
"During the reign of the last Emperor,”
老子是光绪三十一年
Iwas bestowed a Martial Scholar.
皇上钦点的武举人
My rank was higher than yours.
论官职 比你官大
You should kneel in front of me!
你应该给老子跪下
Kneel!
跪下
This is bullshit!
还皇上
The last Emperor? Havel ever met him?
也个皇上 我见过吗
“If you'd been a Literary Scholar,”
你要是个文举人
he'd have to kowtow 200 times.
他应该给你石两百个头
“But as a Martial Scholar,”
可惜你只是个武举人
you'll get only 100 kowtows.
他只能给你奢一百个头
"Since he has already clone 200,”
现在他两百个头奢完了
you've to return 100 kowtows.
你还他一百个
But I've only kowtowed twice!
可我只奢了两个
Does it really matter?
两个也得还你一百个
Do it!
奢不奢
Flog him!
打
That's no good. This is more effective.
这个不好使 得使这个
Stop! I'll do it.
哎 别打 我奢
Splendid.!
听着
"You kowtow, and you cdo the counting.”
你石头 你数数
"One, two, three, four...”
一二三四五六.….
"Hail, Governor!"
青天大老爷
Stand up everyone!
起来 不准跪
No one is worth kneeling to.
皇上都没了 没人值得你们跪
Least of all to me!
我也不值你们跪
I've brought three things to Goose Town.
我来忽城只办三件事
“Justice,”
公平
and goddamned justice.
还是公平
"Hail, Governor!"
青天大老爷
Stand up! No kneeling!
站起来 不准跪
That's better.
这就对了
No kneeling?
不准跪
"He was not only flogging me,”
这酵是打我的屁股
he was slapping you in the face!
这明明是打您的脸
"When my butts stop hurting,”
老爷 等我把屁股养好了
I will personally avenge you.
我亲手给你报优
Summon the noodle vendor.
那就把卖凉粉的叫来
“If our governor loves to try,”
县长喜欢判案
we'll give him a case to try.
就安排一点案子给他判星
"Pop, you were brilliant today.”
欧 今天你这县长干得真漂亮
Flogging that martial scholar was a hoot!
打武举人打得真过瘾
I'd love to be a governor one day.
将来我也想当县长
I don't want you to be a bandit or politician.
你不能当县长 也不许当土匪
"When your father entrusted you to me,”
你驳死的时候把你交给我
Il promised I'd raise you properly.
我答应过他 要让你有出息
Then what should I do?
那我当什么才有出息
Study and learn to enjoy this.
当学生 读书 多听这个
There is no sound!
没声啊
Politicians only know how to bully.
这帮买官的县长 就知道捞钱
"This gramophone was broken,”
唱机都摇坏了
Now it is fixed.
修好了
"Once we're done here,”
这单活于完了 驳赚了钱
ll let you study abroad.
我送你去留洋
"3 years in the east,”
东洋三年
"3 in the west,"
西洋三年
and 3 more in the south.
南洋三年
How about 3 years in the north?
北洋 北洋三年
"No, you're born in the north.”
傻孩子 你生在北洋 不必留了
I think it's Wolfgang.
听着像穆扎
Sometime known as Amadeus.
他们那边叫穆扎
We call him M-o-z-a-r-t.
咱们这边叫莫札特
You can tell by listening?
你还能听出来是谁吹的呢
It depends.
得分时候
On what?
什么时候
If his name was printed there.
那上面印着他名字的时候
"Pop, this Mozart..."
欧 这叫穆扎这人
How did he get the sound in there?
他是怎么把这东西吹到这里边的
You'll learn by studying abroad.
你去留完洋 你就什么都知道了
Where's this Mozart?
那这个穆扎在哪儿
How can I find him?
我留洋的时候要去桂找他
He is far away from us.
他蚜 离咱们很远
Know what you have to do?
怎么做 知道了吗
Yes.
知道了
Who ordered you to co this?
谁让你去做的 你也知道了吗
Did I tell you to do it?
是老爷叫你去的吗
"Yes, sir. You did.”
是 是老爷让我去的
"No, it's "me!"
我
You?
你
"You, you yourself!”
你 你自己
"Yes, me and me alone.”
我自己 我自己
I can't hear you.
听不见
It's my own plot.
是我自己要去的
There are no co-conspirators.
没有人让我去 是我自己
Saviour! My saviour!
恩人恩人
Saviour!
恩人
You're addressing me?
你是叫我呢
Since when have l become your saviour?
我什么时候成你恩人了
"You spared my life,”
不杀之恩为大恩
and I'll save yours in return.
为报不杀之恩 我也救你一命
Do tell.
政 你快说
Never sleep with a widow.
守妇 不能睡啊
It's very bad luck!
必有大灾
Is she really a widow?
真的是寡妇么
She doesn't act like one.
我看着不像
But! witnessed her husband drowned!
我亲眼看见他丈夫济死的
“If she really is a widow,”
她已经成了嘉妇
Then I must not...
我不能.…
leave her alone uncomforted.
让她再守活守
That's my first move.
这是第一步
Within three...
三步之内…
“they'll either leave with tails between their legs,”
要不让他们滚蛋走人
or stay and become our poodles!
要不让他们跪下当狗
"Right, absolutely right.”
对 非常对
"You're looking for me, sir?”
老爷 您找我
Have you entertained our new officials yet?
官府的人还没来
Not yet.
没有
The Governor doesn't frequent brothels?
县长不嫖妓
He'll never make a good governor.
不好色的县长 不一定是好县长
I don't indulge much in sex.
我就是不好色
So you won't make a good governor either.
所以您当不了县长
Why is that so?
我当不了县长
The two bear no comparison!
县长哪能跟您比蚜
Governors come and go.
他只是流水的县长
"But you, sir, will always be our godfather!"
您才是铁打的老爷
You speak welll!
你真会讲话
I'm sure they will come.
他们一定会来 你要好好记住
“Eavesdrop their every conversation,”
他们讲的每一名有用的话
report their every move.
都要回来跟我汇报
Yes.
电 下
Go now. Just don't become a Mata Hari!
走吧 你不要变成小凤仙路
"Who's Mata Hari, Master?”
老爷 谁是小凤仙
What kind of whore are you?
小凤仙都不知道还当妓女
She's the world's most infamous double agent!
那可是名震京城 誉满全国的妓女
You two can leave.
你们出去吧 是
Now the Governor is in bed with his wife.
县长此刻正怀抱夫人 共枕同眠
Let him enjoy one more night in peace!
让他睡最后一个安稳赏
"The Governor's boy is in trouble,”
县长公子 以身试法
your presence is requested at the teahouse.
讲茶大堂 恭迎大驾
Why don't they convene at the magistracy?
讲茶大堂 县衙不是判案的地方吗
The magistracy is just for show.
你这个县衙是摆设
All cases are tried at the teahouse.
判案只有去讲茶大堂 那才是真县衙
"Master Six,”
六和爷
"you've eaten two bowls of jelly,”
你吃了两碗的粉
and paid only for one.
只给了一碗的钱
Bullshit! l have only eaten one bowl!
放屁 我就吃了一碗的粉
And I paid him for one.
给了他一碗的钱
How many bowls did he eat?
他吃了几砚
Two...
两碗
No way!
不可能
"Master Six is the Governor's godson,”
六和爷是县长的儿子
why would he want to cheat you?
怎么能欠你的粉钱呢
But he ate two bowls and paid for one.
就是吃了两碗 只给了一碗的钱
The Governor brings justice to our town.
县长要给我们忽城一个公平
Good!
好
And justice is what I seek today!
我今天讨的就是一个公平
Hear hear!
对
"From the Governor's son, of course.”
问谁讨 问县长儿子 为什么
"Ate two bowls, paid for one!”
他吃了两碗粉 只给了一碗的钱
That's so wrong!
这就叫作不公平
"Since his boy is guilty of unjust,”
既然县长儿子带头不公平
the Governor's crusade is bullshit!
那县长说的话就是个屁
Screw youl!
我操
Master Six...
六和爷.…
Master Six is the Governor's godson!
胡万 六仓是县长的儿子
Would he cheat over a bowl of jelly?
怎么会欠他的粉钱呢
Did you see it with your own eyes?
你亲眼看见了
You double-crosser! What's wrong with you?
你个吃里仆外的东西 怎么着
You're thinking with your butts?
屁股不疼了
It's not about my butts.
今不聊屁股的事
We're here for the truth!
就聊凉粉
One or two bowls?
一碗就是一碗 两碗就是两碗
No beating about the bush!
不能含糊
"Ladmire your courage, sir.”
六和仓 汉子 佩服
I know how to count!
一就是一 二就是二
late only one bowl!
我今天就吃了一碗凉粉
You ate two and paid for one.
你给了一碗的钱 吃了两碗粉
“If you can't afford it, my treat!”
你没钱是吧 我帮你给
I can afford all the jelly in this world!
看见了吗 多少碗我都付得起
But I pay only for what I ate.
但是吃一碗的粉 就给一碗的钱
How many bowls did he eat?
这么多钱 他吃了多少砚粉啊
Let's be frank.
你早说不就得了吗
He wants to be treated fairly.
他要个公平
It's wrong to bully a commoner.
你不是欺负老实人吗
Are you an honest person?
告诉我 你是老实人吗
"Yes, lam..."
我是
How many bowls cid I eat?
那你就说实话 我到底吃了几碗粉
Tell him!
你告诉他
Speak up!
你说不说
Stop threatening this poor man with a gun!
拿枪吓路一可怜的 卖凉粉的
Who doesn't carry a gun around here?
有枪是吧 谁没有枪啊
Noodle vendor! How many bowls did he eat?
孙守义 大声说 他吃了几砚
“Everyone in this teahouse,”
守义 在座所有的乡亲
will bear witness on your behalf.
都会为你和你的家人作主的
Speak up! How many?
大声说 几砚
Two bowls.
两碗
You're nasty!
你是一个恶人
But I dare you to match me!
比恶是吧 我比你还恶
Take a good look!
都看好了啊
"If there are two bowls of jelly in me, I'll die!”
今我肚子里要有两砚粉 我白死
“If there's only one, I'll die.”
你要是肚子里只有一碗粉 我死
"If he has two bowls in him, I'll die with him!"
要是有两碗粉 我陪六爷一起死
Where's the jelly?
凉粉呢
Deeper! I can't see.
太浅了 我看不见
"Very gutsy, sir!”
六爷 佩服
"Try sliding the blade sideway,”
凉粉在肠子里 你得横着拉一下
so that we can all see.
才能让我看得见
Show us if there is one or two bowls.
六和爷 让大家看看是一砚还是两砚
Out with it!
拉
"Here's a bowl, sir.”
六爷 砚
See! Can you see?
看见了吧 看见了吧
One bowl!
是不是只有一碗
Hang in there! I'll get a doctor!
六和爷 挺住 我去给你请大夫
Your turn!
该你了
I knew it all along.
我知道你只吃了一砚
You fell for it.
你上当了
"You mustn't kill him! No, l won't!"
不能杀… 我不能放
"Tell me why! should spare him,”
为什么不能杀
“or I'll shoot you, too.”
说不出说法来 我把你一起杀了
Don't let Six die in vain!
杀了他 六子白死
I didn’t do it. He stabbed himself.
我没有杀他 他自己捅自己的
We'd a wager.
我们在打赌
He lost.
他输了
Let me blast his head off!
我一枪崩了他 大哥 你让我一枪崩了他
You wouldn't dare! You can't do it.
你不敢杀我 你不能杀我
Huang is provoking you.
黄四郎就想看你这样
He wants you to lose your head.
一脸的败相
We'll lose if we kill him now.
杀了他就是输 不杀还能赢
Let him go.
放人
You must destroy Huang’s soul!
杀人诛心 杀人诛心
". Pop, he's right. - Let him go!”
师爷说得对 放人
He stabbed himself? What about the jelly?
刀进了肚子 那凉粉还是凉粉
Yes
电 下
and no...
不是
Tell me if it was still jelly.
我就想知道 凉粉到底还是不是凉粉
"Yes, it was.”
是凉粉
And...
那么…
is he dead?
人死了
Yes.
死了
Did you implicate me?
所以…你就把我供出来了
Idid invoke your name.
我是用老爷的名字吓距他们
Were they scared?
他们被吓着了吗
"They said to kill, a person's soul must first be destroyed.”
他们说杀人诛心
Murder? Soul destruction?
杀人还要诛心
How awful.
好可怕啊
"Brother, l vow to avenge you!”
六弟 四哥发誓替你报优
"Brother, l swear I'll avenge you!”
六弟 五哥发拆替你报优
Two is drunk. lam pledging for him.
二哥喝醇了 他让我带话
"He will avenge your death, too.”
二哥发誓替你报信
"Brother, l swear to avenge you!”
六弟 三哥发誓替你报优
"Two is sober, he's just pissed off!”
二哥没喝醇 他生气了
Chief doesn't want to risk our lives.
大哥不想让大伙拼命
Are we boy scouts or what?
命都不拼 还算麻匪吗
Chief should have ignored Tang.
大哥不应该听他的
He is a good-for-nothing!
姓汤的不是个好玩意
Huang kills without lifting a finger!
六爷 黄四郎这招叫杀人不用刀
We must retaliate by destroying his soul.
我给你人移出的招叫杀人诛心
We can't jeopardise our chance to get rich!
不能拼命啊 拼命还怎么赚钱
Six...
六子
Ido not care about being rich.
赚钱对我算个事儿吗
But Il must come up with a game plan
我不是要杀人诛心 是没想出好办法
to rid of Huang once and for all
我要把黄四郎连根都拔掉
"Give me time,"
给我点时间
Pop will avenge your death.
六子 欧发誓一定给你报优
Show your respect!
把脸收拾收拾
“Have a safe journey, Six.”
六爷 一路走好
How should I play my hand?
先打蛙一张牌
“Banquet, kill him or throw him to the dogs?”
请客 斩首 收下当狗
ld say kill him!
斩
No!
错
Host a banquet!
请客
Dinner invitation! It's a death trap!
鸿门宴 凶多吉少
Our ploy is working!
杀人诛心 赫然奏效
lI have another idea: delay tactics.
我再送你一个字
The longer we drag this on the better!
拉 拉得越久 赚得越多
Huang will end up kneeling here.
到时候跪在这儿的就是黄四郎本人
What kind of banquet is this?
什么鸿门宴
It's just a meeting between two thugs!
就是恶霸请土匪
It's like MacBeth hosting Banquo.
项羽请刘邦啊
What'd become of Banquo the guest?
刘邦后来于什么去了
His son became king.
当皇帝了
And MacBeth the host?
项羽呢
So we should go.
那 赴宴
"We can also sound out Huang,”
赴宴 正好借机把黄四郎也笼络过来
and see if we can work together.
咱们三个联手一起捞钱
Got it!
明白
You see Six's death as a shortcut to bonanza?
老汤 你是把六子的死当捞钱的成本了
Perhaps your severed head can make us more.
我看你当成本 赚的钱会更多
What do you mean?
这是什么意思
Let's go and meet your new pal.
走 去会会你的新朋友
Attention!
立正
"Governor, counselor! Welcome!"
县长、师苑 大驾光临 有失远迎
Master's citadel dominates Goose Town.
黄老爷的宅妓 竹林掩映 再楼疮立
Itis simply impregnable.
易守难攻 万夫莫开
“An intrepid governor, an erudite counselor.”
县长英雄气概 师爷文采斐然
What a dream team!
珠联莒合 二位请
Master Six has died heroically.
六爷的死 壮烈
I've invited you here today
今天请县长来
to witness how justice is done.
就是要当面为六爷讨回这个公道
“If I'm proven to be the instigator,”
如果真的是黄某指使
"I will follow Master Six's footstep,”
那我就像六爷一样
and disembowel myself!
当众剖腹自杀
"Linvite you to be my second,”
不但自杀 还请县长您
to ritualistically cut my head off
当我的介错人
and hang it from the restaurant.
砍下我人头 高挂艳阳楼顶
“If I'm proven innocent, those who slandered me”
万一不是我 那就是辱我名声
and shamed you in the process...
欺骗县长
will have to kill themselves.
你们自裁
It's me against these three.
要么三命抵一命 要么随时告发我
lam reacly.
我随时死
You should use this for disembowelment.
黄老爷 我听说自裁用短刀
The full blade is for your second.
长刀归介错人
Really?
是吗
It's great to have an expert as my second!
果然在行 县长随时可以当我的介错人
"This way, please.”
马县长 请
I bought this governorship.
马某人这个县长 买来的
Sole purpose is to get rich.
买官就是为了赚钱
But I don't take from the poor.
而且 马某人不喜欢赚穷人的钱
Then who are you targeting?
那你想赚谁的钱呢
Who are the wealthy?
那谁有钱
Such as you.
你有钱
"Whatever you fancy, help yourself.”
豆快 县长看上什么了 随便拿
I'm no bandit. 'm a governor.
我不是土菲 我是县长
I make my fortune the proper way.
县长赚钱得讲究个名正言顺才是
Well said!
说得好
Goose Town has two big families.
我们忽城有两大家族
"They sell people to America to build railroads,"
都是把人卖到美国修铁路
What do you mean by dolls?
还说刀的事
"No, d-o-I-l-a-r-s! American money.”
不是…美金是美国人用的钱
Dollar! You know?
美金 懂吗
"Oh, dollars!"
美金 收到了
Ican smell it in your presence!
黄老爷一来 钱就到了
Let's drink to that!
喝一杯吧
"Great, cheers!"
好来
Master Huang is so modest.
黄老爷 客气了
"It is an open secret that,”
整个南国谁不知道
"in Goose Town, Master Huang is our real boss!"
在苇城 你黄四郎是老大
It is hard to be a boss.
老大往往是空架子
Hundreds of people everyday
每天眼一有睁 几百人吃、喝、拉、投
waiting to be fed.
都要等着我伺候
There is little left for me.
真正落到我嘴里的 能有几口
"If you're looking to make a fast buck,”
如果县长真的急着赚钱
I know exactly what to do.
我倒是有个好去处
Please tell.
哦 请讲
Pocky Zhang!
张麻子
One of them just died!
真死了
"Yes, Pocky Zhang!"
对 张麻子
What has he got to do with us?
那么这个张麻子 是跟我们有关系呢
Or with our money?
还是跟钱有关系
Everything!
都有关系
Is he here in Goose Town?
莫非他在忽城
and no!
也不在
Master Huang speaks in riddles!
黄老爷这话 还挺有玄机了啊
"Where is he, then?”
这小子到底在哪呢
Let Master Huang enlightens us.
听黄和爷给咱们聊聊 聊聊
He has grabbed Goose Town by its balls!
此人盘中煌城周边交通咽喉
Know what I mean?
明白吗
No.
不明白
Know what do for a living?
我是做什么生意的 明白吗
Half the opium smokers in this nation
小半个民国的烟圭
rely on Master Huang for their supply!
都是黄老爷您在贩卖
"No, I'm only a pawn for General Liu.”
错 我不过是给刘都统当跑腿的
I'm just one of his runners!
而且只是其中一条腿
How many runners does Liu have?
那么刘都统到底有几条腿呢
Three.
三条员
And Master is the most able one!
黄老爷还是条大腿
"Yes, the strongest one!”
对 大腿
“But this runner,”
可是我这条腿…
is now crippled!
断了
What happened?
怎么断的
Zhang has seized nearly all my goods.
我的货十回有八回被张麻子友走了
Imagine what he can make from them.
你想想 他赚了多少钱
He must be very well off!
那这个张麻子很富有啊
l wonder if this is true.
还有这种事儿
"You can write your own cheque,”
如果你们可以去某菲的话
if you can take him out!
钱要多少有多少
We wouldn't dare to!
我们没胆子荐菲
"But if this can make us rich,”
但是 借荐菲之名生财的胆子还是有
I wouldn't mind having a go!
而且很大
Then blame yourself for your timidity!
那就不要怪我 就怪你们没出息
But I would be happy to assist.
不过 我还可以帮你们一个忙
I can put up money as a bait.
我出钱 当诱饵
The families have to match my contribution.
我出多少 两大家族必须出多少
We're hoping you'd say that.
就等您这句话呢 足够
"How about $800,000?"
那您出八十万
No! I'll put up $1.8 million!
不 我出一百八十万
"Yes, we'll pay you back $1.8 million,”
明白 事成之后 一百八十万如数奉还
and split the dollars from the others.
咱们分两大家族那点儿钱
There's no need to pay him back!
一百八十万不用还
We'll hit these bandits hard!
不就是某匪么 制
"Whatever they seized in the past,”
咱们把张麻子动走的那点钱
we will retrieve for the Master.
全拿回来 还给黄老爷
“Look at the bigger picture,”
到那个时候
the $1.8 million bounty is but a strand of hair.
这一百八十万就是九牛身上的一根毛
Surely you won't mind!
您还在意吗
We'll get rid of Pocky Zhang!
不就是个小小的张麻子吗 办他
Cool!
硬
Cool enough?
硬吗
Very cool!
够硬
We can discuss that later.
硬不硬以后再说
The only thing I want to do now
我脑子里想的只有一件事
is to fix Master's crippled leg.
替黄老爷把这条腿接上
Pocky Zhang's such a nuisance.
一个张麻子也太串张了
He shouldn't have messed with Master Huang!
欺负到黄届头上了 不答应
Let's top up.
喝酒 有了有了 我自己喝
"Il believe in taking our time,”
我以为 酒一口一口喝
doing things step by step!
路一步一步走
I don't want to break my balls
步子迈大了 喀
by over-stretching!
容易一场空
"We should agree on the split first,”
应该先把钱分清楚
before thinking of how to fix his leg.
再说接腿的事儿
“If you want to settle the split now,”
你还聊钱是吧 不聊接腿
then just carry on.
那你们俩聊吧
"Counselor, you decide.”
师爷 你定
“About the dollars,” !
先聊钱吧
let's do a customary 30-70 split.
钱到手 按照惯例 三七分
How can you even say that?
你也太不仗义了吧
Master Huang is so instrumental.
黄老爷为这事忙前忙后
And you give him only 30%?
你就分人家三成
Let's go 50-50!
怎么也得对半分啊
"My apologies, Master Huang.”
那我…那我错了
So inconsiderate!
你太错了
"Counselor, I'll go along with that: 50-50."
师爷 我们还是听县长的 对半分
“If you've the guts to take on the bandits,”
如果真有胆子某匪
“the dollars from the two families,”
两大家族的钱
are but strands of hair!
就值一根毛
Strands of hair!
一根毛
May not be even that!
于是一根啊
I know you have the courage.
胆子你是有的
But ability-wise...?
本事呢
How do I know if you can overcome Zhang?
我赁什么相信你能草张麻子
"May lask you a question, sir?”
黄老爷 容兄弟问你个问题
Go ahead.
请
"If Zhang can seize your goods,”
张麻子能友你的货
why can't he break in here?
为什么不能进你的家呢
My citadel is impregnable.
我这克楼 固若金汤
There's no way that he can get in.
易守难攻 他进不来
Are you sure
那你怎么就真的相信
that we're the only ones here?
只有我跟师和爷 进了你的再楼呢
An order to retreat!
说让咱们撤
- Split? - You sure?
撤 那撤吧
Let's split.
撤
Did you hear that?
听见了吧
Yes.
听见了
"Where Pocky fails to breach, I succeeded!"
张麻子进不来的地方 我能进来
I can kill him when he is least expecting it.
张麻子不想死的时候 我能让他死
Another one bites the dust!
又死一个
Implicate me for all you like.
你们可以把我供出来嘛
I couldn't care less!
不要委屈自己政
Governor. l sense that you're special.
马县长 我早看出 你非等闲之辈
lam flattered.
不敢当
"But those who waged war on the bandits, none has survived.”
不过 有胆子荐菲的人 九死一生
Why not?
何以见得
Pocky Zhang is a tough cookie.
张麻子非同凡人
I met him once 20 years ago.
二十年前 我们有过一面之缘
Isn't that fate?
竟有如此的缘分
How did it happen?
那么 缘从何起呢
"He stood by a lantern and turned towards me,”
灯火阑珊 他暮然回首
and I was standing in the shade.
而我 却隐藏在灯影里
“He was well lit up, and you're in the dark!”
一个在明处 一个在暗处
"Quiet, quiet...”
呈 安静一点
So it was there and then...
那么彼时彼刻…
"A bit like, here and now!"
恰如此时此刻
What a coincidence!
竟能如此相像
Exactly!
像 很像
But you're missing something.
不过.…你比他缺了一样东西
You mean his facial scars?
不会是脸上的麻子吧
Of course not.
当然不是
Then what is it?
那么是什么呢
You don't know how to play act.
你不会装糊涂
Exactly!
准
A fortune teller told my mother
大哥 我还在娘胎里的时候
before l was even born!
算命先生就指着我娘的肚子说
He said my Achilles heel
这孩子将来最大的缺点
would be my inability to play act!
就是不会装糊涂
Can I change it?
大哥 我还能改吗
No way! It's in your genes!
改不了 天生的
But our counselor is a born actor!
你看看这位师爷 就是装糊涂的高手
Confusing dollar with dolls?
把钱说成刀
What is dollar?
钱 是什么钱
American money!
是美元
A genius when it comes to play acting.
你看你看 装糊涂的天才啊
"Counselor, cheers!"
师爷 敬你的
"Thanks for your compliment, sir.”
谢黄老爷颂扬
Allow me to play the fool for once.
容老弟真的糊涂一回
“After defeating the bandits,”
某菲成功之后 追回的烟土
we'll take just 20% of any opium recovered.
我们只要两成就够
"No, Linsist 50-50!"
不行 对半开
I'll send over $1.8 million now.
一百八十万 马上送来
That's too soon. We haven't started yet!
无功不受禄 现在收钱太早
"Marie, Claire!”
全玉 畏零
"Master, I can't take women.”
大哥 美女我也不能要
"No interest in money or women,”
美女不要 钱你也不要
what do you want?
你要什么啊
Arunner.
服
What runner?
什么腿啊
Master Huang’s a runner of exceptional courage!
江湖豪情、侠胆柔肠之大腿
Brother!
ET 可
We can run side by side!
弟
"Roads won't exist in this world of chaos,"
有道是 江湖本无路
unless people like us run on them!
有了腿 便有了路
"Il see, I see...”
明白 明白
"Yes, me too.”
我也明白
Stupid bitch!
该死的东西
"While flowers can blossom again,”
花有重开日
time lost will never return.
人无再少年
This girl is as delicate as jade.
姑娘如花似玉
Please don't be mad at her.
大哥 怒不得啊
"Master Huang, easy easy...”
黄老爷 轻松点
Shame we didn't meet until now!
相见恨晚
"Diamonds, the girl - they're all yours.”
姑娘、钻石一并送上
I've brought my wife with me.
唉 我带夫人来的
So I can't take her home.
再收姑娘不方便
Then take the diamonds for your wife.
那钻石送夫人
l accept them on her behalf.
好 我先蔡她收着
Get up.
起来吧
I thought you'd summoned two girls.
不是代玉和了畏零吗
How come there's only her?
怎么就来了一名女子
You mean she is Marie-Claire?
莫非她就叫繁玉畏堆
You are really na?vel
说你不会装糊涂吧
She's adopted a fashionable name.
起了个东洋名字
It's Marie-Claire!
合玉了畏堆子
There goes the last of them!
全死了
A wise counselor! !
师爷 高
A tough governor!
县长 硬
"Master, you're both wise and tough.”
黄老爷又高又硬
"Are you really "Pocky Zhang?”
你到底是不是张麻子
Supposing that you are.
要说你是吧
You've already made a fortune
扭断刘都统大腿
“from crippling’ Liu's runners.”
琶那么多钱
Why bother with Goose Town?
何苦进城当县长呢
But if you are someone else...
要说你不是吧…
Saviour?
恩人
Kill the chicken and take the eggs.
今晚 杀鸡取卵
Let him die in his own bed.
一定要在县长的床上
Don't kill him on his way home
不要让人以为吃了我的饭
after dining as my guest.
死在我家里 死在半路上
Understood!
明白
"Who is the ""chicken""'?”
蛙个是鸡
The Governor.
县长
"And the "eggs?"
那么卵呢
I'll cut his balls off!
是不是把县长给阅了
My two diamonds!
我的两颗钻石
"Don't worry, sit!”
老爷放心 你要的钻石
I'll retrieve your diamonds.
我这就给你弄回来
I'm sorry.
对不起
Know why I'm sending you?
明白不明白 为什么派你去
It's because I'm already dead.
因为我死了
Do you know why?
为什么你会死呢
I shouldn't have implicated you.
因为我把老爷给供出来了
"Right! If you are alive, you'll eventually die.”
对陵 如果你活着 早晚都会死
"But if you're dead,”
如果你死了
you may live on forever!
你永远都活着
Understood.
明白
"Kill the chicken, take the eggs!”
杀鸡取卵
Where's Chief?
师爷 大哥呢
Punch drunk!
马上 喝醇了
Where is he?
人呢 哪儿呢
We're still chatting just now!
刚才还说话呢
"IT must be drunk, too!”
我也喝醇了
lll sort you out later.
回来跟你算帐
He must've fallen off the horse.
没在马上么 是不是掉路上了
lheard that you slept.
听说你睡觉了
Look up when you speak.
你抬起头来跟我说话
l heard that you slept last night.
听说你昨天睡觉了
I sleep every goddamned night!
我哪天不睡觉啊
Look at me when you speak.
你看着我说话
You slept with the bandit?
听说你跟土匪睡觉了
Do you want a blow-by-blow account?
睡了 你不想知道我们怎么睡的吗
Tell me more.
对 怎么睡的
"When a seasoned pro meets a bandit chief,”
一个青楼女子 跟一个土匪头子
anything could happen!
什么睡法都能有
What now?
喊什么咕
Whore! Bitch! Vixen! Tramp!
你这个不要脸的骚窗姐 寻子 贱货
What did you call me?
你说什么
"If 'cl more time,”
就是时间不够
lll put you in your place!
要不然我活活把你给搞死了
Come on!
好啊 来呀
Idare you!
看你怎么办
You're all talk!
你就只剩下一张嘴
“A perverted, dirty old man.”
写几个烂戏本的老色鬼
Could you have bought the post without my money?
不是我出钱 谁给你买官当县长啊
Don't piss me off!
你别台急我了
I think the bandit is more able!
我还真觉得那个土匪挺有本事的
What do you mean?
他算什么本事啊
He's got more balls than you!
比你有本事
He's good at getting drunk!
早烂醇如泥了
These will make your day!
这才是真本事
Three of Huang's clogs died today.
六子 黄四郎今天死了三条狗
I know they're not worthy of you.
我知道 狗命抵不了你的命
"was going to lead our brothers,”
我本来带着弟兄们
“engage Huang in a deadly duel,”
要跟黄四郎拼个鱼死网破
and avenge your death.
给你报优
But I've changed my mind.
可是中途我改了主意
I can't take revenge this way.
鱼死网破报不了优
I can't risk more lives.
弟兄们不能再死人了
"Chief, we're looking for you.”
大哥 你怎么在这儿啊
Why did you signal retreat?
你怎么让我们撤了吓
Huang heard your whistling.
黄四郎听见你们吹的哨声
I knew that I was safe.
我就绝对安全了
"Leave, I want to spend time alone with Six.”
去吧 我跟六子单独待会儿
“It has finally dawned on me,”
今天我算明白了
why I became a bandit in the first place.
为什么当初我会上山当麻菲
I was no match for these people.
就是因为跟这帮和东西玩不起
"But l must take them on at their own game now,”
现在为了你 我必须玩得起
What the heck?
谁
You stole my diamonds.
偷我的钻石
They're not meant for you.
这石头是给你的吗
They're a gift for Mrs. Governor!
是给县长夫人的
Which of us is the Governor?
咱们俩谁是县长
Who's the Governor?
谁是县长
Tell me who's the Governor!
我问你呢 谁是县长
You want to kill me?
你是要杀我
Is there a difference?
有什么不一样吗
It's different!
不一样啊
"Lcan bed you first, and kill you later.”
那就先睡 再杀
Then you'd better kill me now.
那还是杀了我吧
I don't sleep with dead bodies!
杀了你 我还怎么睡啊
"lL won't take drunken advantage of a widow,”
我不能酒后欺负一个嘉妇
"so I'll just sleep next to you,”
是跟你睡
not with youl!
不是睡你
Holy smoke! I was fooled!
我居然上了你们的当
You and Wu both faked death!
你和武举人都是假死是吧
That's right.
不错
Why dressed up as a bandit?
为什么冒充订匪
"I'm a bandit. ""Pocky' Zhang's my boss!"
老子就是麻菲 张麻子是我大哥
"What's your rank, then?”
那你是老几呀
lam Three!
老三
"Three, you've hit big time!”
老三 你出名了
You've got yourself a fake!
有人冒充你了
"Chief, con't listen to his bullshit!"
别听他废话了 大哥
He plotted Six's death.
六子就死在他手上
Let me shoot him now!
你让我一枪崩了他
Chief?
大哥
"Were you sent by "Pocky" Zhang?”
是你大哥张麻子派你来的
Or by Master Huang?
还是你老爷黄四郎派你来的
I want the right answer!
不能说错啊
Master Huang.
黄老爷
Why?
为什么
"We commit crimes posing as bandits,”
他让我们假扮廊菲在城里抢劫
forcing governors to launch expeditions.
他通县长下令葛菲
Creating more chances for Huang to swindle.
骗豪绅 刮百姓
And then?
然后呢
That's all.
没了
Really?
其他事我真不知道
Why did you target my bed?
为什么朝我床上开枪
"Master said you're arrogant,”
黄老爷说你霸气外露
a threat!
危险
Take him a message:
回去给他带个话 告诉他
"While he likes people to fake death,”
他喜欢让人假死这一套
I'm fond of killing people more than once!
正好 我也喜欢让人多死几回这一套
Letting me off again?
您要放我回去
He can only understand words you say.
只有你的话他听得懂
"Chief, you're...”
大哥 可您到底是
"Yes, Pocky’ Zhang.”
不错 张麻子
Where are your pockmarks?
可大哥您脸上没麻子
“Does your boss have Huang” inscribed on his face?”
黄四郎验上有四吗
That's true.
懂了
"My friend,”
兄弟
"you must not tell anyone,”
我是张麻子这件事
"[ never want to be a governor,”
我说我当不了县长
but you still bought me this post!
你非花钱让我买这个官
"The position has been usurped,”
现在官被人家抢走了
and now you're dead too.
你也就这么死了
Huang has brought his militia.
黄四郎带人来了
Wanting to fight bandits with us.
说是要帮有我们打麻菲
She was my wife.
她是我老婆
lam the governor!
我是县长
Let him in.
让他进来
lam Ma Bangde!
我就是马邦德
Is the Governor okay?
县长如何了 县长如何了
Give chase! Don't let anyone get away.
你们追 一个麻菲也不能跑
Those goddamned bandits!
天杀的订菲
Scum of the earth!
伤天害理
The Governor has only just arrived...
县长刚刚上任 竟和他的夫人双双.…
"Said I didn't want to be a governor,”
我说我当不了这个县长
but you still bought me this post!
你非得给我花钱买这个官
"The governership is now mine,”
现在官倒是到手了
but you've left me on my own.
你倒这么走了
She was my wife.
她是我老婆
lam the governor!
我就是县长
lam Ma Bangde!
我就是马邦德
You're too hot-headed.
你呀 太年轻了
You shouldn't have shot those bandits.
不该一进城就枪此麻菲
They'll take revenge for sure.
他们一定会报复你的
Don't cry.
不哭 不器
She deserves a proper burial!
得厚匡她呀
Invite every townsfolk to attend.
得让所有的乡绅都过来
Certainly. I'll take care of it.
都来都来 我会安排
..to be relieved of life’s burden.
.…放下今生的担子
Thus we commit their bodies to earth.
我们就亲切的将他放入土中
"From which they came,”
他们本是尘土
and do now return.
现在 他们依然是尘土
"We know we can place ourselves,”
我们知道 这一切的生命气息
"in the hands of our Father in Heaven,”
都在永生的慈爱的天父手里
who has promised us eternal life.
而且他应允将永生…
"We're from "Pocky" Zhang's gang.”
我们是张麻子张大爷的队伍
We're here for the money.
要钱 不要命
Sorry for the intrusion!
各位乡绅受惊了
We're looking for...
我们今天就是来找几个人
“Huang, heads of families, show yourselves!"
黄四郎 城南两大家族 站出来
Hu Wan?
胡万
"Father, our apologies.”
神父 打扰了
“Ladies and gentlemen,”
各位父老
the rest has nothing to do with this.
剩下的事情就与你们无关了
Leave!
再见
Gag them!
入袋
Get up!
起来
I'm the governor of this county.
好汉 我是本县县长
Il volunteer to be your hostage.
要绑 绑我吧
Just shut up!
你不说话不行吗
We spare you to deliver our ransom.
留着你的命 活着蔡我们收钱
"Three days, pay up and they go home.”
三天之内 钱到 放人
“If not, they die.”
钱不到 捧票
- Shoot me first! - Stop it!
打死我吧 .… 别打别打
You're asking for it.
找打是吧
Beat him up!
打.…
You talk too much!
你怎么这么多中啊
I'll teach you a lesson!
让你多嘴…
Stop messing with my mask!
你装模作样的戴我的九简于什么
Don't screw things up.
别把事给我办砸了
Take them away!
带走
-It's him. - Three!
是他 老三
No one goes until we get his ransom.
不见钱不放人啊
"Butler, stay calm!"
于哥 忍着
"One, two, three..."
一一 -一一
Huang is in there!
黄四郎在里头
You plotted this scheme
你抱着我夫人学我哭的时候
over my wife's dead body?!
就想到这招了
lam impressed!
有粗有细啊
We'll kill the hostages in 3 days!
三天之内 钱不到就据票
"Remember, lam Nine!”
记着 我是九简
That was quite a show.
这活办的真爽快
- Almost pass for real! - Sure.
像真的吗” 像
I'll be more convincing with some blood.
要是有人再流点血 就更像真的了
Right!
对
Was that necessary?
有这个必要吗
Was that really necessary?
有这个必要吗 有这个必要吗
Shoot! Give them hell!
给我打 给我狠狠打
"Butler, hold your fire!”
千爷 别打了
We need time to prepare the ransom.
赶紧回去备银子吧
Otherwise they will kill the hostages.
三天收不到钱 麻菲可是要撕票的
Let them kill the hostages.
撕 让他们所
"In fact, l want them dead!"
一定要让他们撕
Why do you think I need a double?
替身就是为我于这个的
lll not pay any ransom.
这个钱 我一分钱都不出
But the families will pay up.
不过两大家族的钱
You'll get your money for sure.
一定会过你们的手
“Brother,”
弟弟
I'm fine.
不要为我担心啊
Don't worry about me.
于万不要为我担心
Hu Wan must have defected to Zhang.
老爷 我怀疑胡万投靠了张麻子
"He must be found,”
一定要找到胡万
dead or alive!
活要见人 死要见忆
"A double is useful. Find me one, too.”
替身这么有用啊 得空帮有我也找一个
"Pocky, have you no shame?”
张麻子 你真是死不要脸
The game's up!
玩砸了
Really?
砸了吗
"Yes, game's up.”
砸了
The fun has only just begun.
我怎么觉得…刚开始啊
Amen!
阿门
Release them.
放人
Here's a souvenir. Don't look back. Scram!
给你们留个纪念 不准回头 滚
"Ma'am, if you're still alive,”
夫人 你要是晚走两天
you'd see this for yourself.
就能亲眼看见了
"If she was alive, there'll be nothing here.”
嫂子要是不走 这钱都到不了这桌上
She traded her life for this.
对 我老婆的命换来的这些钱
Doesn't Six's life count?
那我们家小六子的命不算命啊
It's different.
那不一样
Goddamned it isn't!
怎么就不一样啊
My wife.
夫人
Whose wife?
谁夫人了岗
Mine.
我夫人
What about her?
你夫人怎么了
She was murdered by Huang.
夫人是被黄四郎杀死的
But Six died at his own hands.
你们家六和爷自残 自杀
"TI shoot you dead,”
我一枪崩了你
for demeaning our Six!
你敢说我们家小六子 找死啊
"Two, put down your gun.”
老二你把枪放下
Stop pointing your gun at me!
别拿枪对着我
I've never seen bandits as dumb as you!
我见过土匪 没见过练肌肉的土匪
Stop laughing! Cut it out.
笑什么啊 别笑 别笑
I didn't belittle Six! He had courage!
我是说你们家六分 你们家六爷这样
He was a hero!
那是英雄
"Yes, he was heroic.”
是 是英雄
"Don't cry! Your wife was heroic, too.”
师爷不哭 媳子也是英雄
"Brothers, why are we here?”
各位哥哥 咱们为什么来了
To get rich!
钱啊
Have we succeeded?
钱到了吗
"Yes, we have.”
到了
So let's leave!
走啊
Why are you still in tears?
那你还哭什么呀
I'm overjoyed.
我可以不器
"Chief, when cdo we leave?”
大哥 什么时候走
We're not.
不走
This is not Huang’s money.
钱不是黄四郎送来的
But the money's still good!
大哥 两大家族的钱不算钱啊
I want Huang’s fortune.
我要的是黄四郎的钱
You refuse to take money from rich or poor...
你不刮穷人的钱 也不要大户的钱…
"The blood debt of Six and Madam,”
六子 夫人 两条命
must be repaid by Huang!
必须黄四郎来偿
You're gambling with our lives!
你这是玩命啊 赌徒
You call this a gamble?
这就算赌了
"Yes, and you'll end up a loser!"
算 就是 还赌不赢
We're not leaving.
人不走
We don't want this money either.
钱也都不要了
Give them away.
发出去
But Chief...
可是 大哥
Who do you want to give this to?
这钱你都发给谁呢
To the poor.
发给穷人鹃
Who are the poor?
那谁是穷人啊
Those in dire need.
谁穷 谁就是穷人
"You wore ""Nine™ when you ambushed me.”
动我的时候 你戴的就是九简
Feel it for yourself.
你自己措摸
™"One™"
一简
"Fun, isn't it?”
过瘤吗
Haven't you always wanted to play God?
你不就是想当老天和爷吗
Yes.
是啊
What has it got to do with Huang?
这跟收拾黄四郎有什么关系呀
"If lam God, tidding him should be a piece of cake.”
老天爷都能当 还收拾不了一个黄四郎
I think l know her.
这个 我认识
So doll
我也认识
Let's give her some money.
给她发点钱吧
Hang on!
于什么呀
"She is not exactly poor, is she?”
大哥说了 发穷人 她不穷
So who are the poor?
那你说 谁算穷人
Those who're forced to sell their own children.
穷人 那就得被逼得卖儿卖女
Correct! She was sold by her parents. !
她 就是被穷人卖掉的女儿
Make sense!
对呀
So you're bandits in disguise!
原来县长的人是麻菲
We've come to give you money.
我们就想给你发点钱
Kill her. No option!
杀 必须的
Whoever sees a bandit's face has to die.
见过麻菲真面目的 必死无疑
It's your own rule.
这可是你下的令
Counselor.
师爷
The first to see our faces
第一个见过麻菲真面目的人
was youl!
是你
“Our mission is only half accomplished,”
事还没办呢就起内证
and we're bickering over a broad!
还为了一个女人
You're the lead drummer at my inauguration?
我进城那天 带头敲鼓的是你吧
What's your name?
姑娘 贵姓
Call me Flora.
免贵 花姐
Are you related to Huang?
不是姓黄吧
"No, he bought me.”
不姓 是黄四郎把我买来的
There are posters by the city gate.
城门口贴的那些告示
Know what they're for?
知道是什么意思吧
"Bounty offers for ""Pocky'” Zhang.”
通缉张麻子的
"Lam "Pocky" Zhang.”
我就是张麻子
The bandits were behind this.
麻菲发的 铁证如山
ls it because of the masks?
用面具的就是麻菲
We have masks tool
我们也有面具
Then it must be the Governor!
那就是县长
He is giving money to the poor?
有钱不赚 发给穷人
No bogus governor would do that.
这像是个买官的县长做的事吗
I want you to dress up as bandits.
今天 我要你们扮成麻菲
Exactly like them.
跟他们一模一样
"What they give out, you take away.”
他们怎么发 你们就怎么抢
Let's cause havoc!
搞乱他们
Understood.
明白
I'll have him checkmate in 3 moves!
三步棋必治他于死地
But we've made 3 moves already.
老爷 三步棋 咱们都已经走完了
Really?
是吗
"Driving Six to death, killing the chicken for the eggs..."
远死小六子 杀鸡取卵…
Those were old moves!
那是老三步了
I'm talking about 3 new moves!
现在我要走的新三步
"First, check out the Governor.”
第一步 到省城查清马邦德
He doesn't act like someone who'd buy a post.
我总觉得他不像是个买官的县长
“At least, he’s not Ma Bangde.”
起码 不姓马
Have you found Hu Wan?
胡万的事怎么样了
Hu Wan? Not yet.
胡万 还没找到
How come he is still missing?
你怎么可能说还没有找到
"Don't worry, sir. I'll find him.”
老爷你放心 我会去找他 继续找
Do you know...
你晓不晓得…
how much I miss him?
我多么的想他
"On master's order, let's wreak havoc!"
黄老爷吟只我们把他们搞乱
Let's show how we can mess things up!
看老子怎么把他们搞乱
Did you get your share?
收到银子了
Yes.
收到了
How are you going to thank us?
那你打算怎么感谢我们
Any way you like.
怎么感谢都.…都行
"Any way I like? Great, you said it!”
怎么感谢都行 你说的 好
Know why we gave you money?
知道我们…为什么会给你发银子吗
It is because you're benevolent.
因为麻菲人苑对我们好
Benevolent?
对你好
We can do even better!
还没好透
"Governor, we want justice!”
青天大老爷做主啊
It's all over! We're finished!
磺了你们 砸了
Even rabbits wouldn't do this.
兔子都知道不吃窝边草
"Six men, in front of her husband,"
六个人 还当着人家丈夫
and in broad daylight!
还让人看
Disgusting!
唾 恶心
I've never even cone this with lights on!
我都关着灯
“If you're desperate, paid for it!”
这种事你们可以花点钱嘛
Be extravagant!
花点
Visit a brothel! !
吾怕嫖呢
It won't cost much!
花不了多少钱
You don't even have to be discreet.
吾怕偷偷摸摸的
This is stupid!
简直就是土匪
You're worse than bandits!
土匪都不如
And we'd wanted to leave a good impression!
还说让人家百姓夸你们好
One word comes to mind: revolting!
就是一句话 恶心
Our scheme is now in ruin!
钱肯定是赚不着了
Disgusting!
恶心 恶心
“Filthy, nauseating...”
恶心呐 恶心
Revolting!
咋 太恶心
You know me.
大哥 你是了解我的
"When it comes to this sort of thing,”
我从来不做仗势欺人的事
I prefer to be passive...
我喜欢被动
"You know me,”
大哥你是了解我的
"Lam a lone wolf,”
以我的习惯
always acting on my own.
万事不求人
"You know me,”
大哥 你是了解我的
"If it was me,"
如果是我…
she wouldn't have lived to squeal.
不会有人活着来告状
You know me.
大哥你是了解我的
"I may be the eldest,”
我老五虽然岁数最大
still a virgin.
俗称处男
Stop staring at me!
别看着我呀
You know me well.
大哥 你是了解我的
"If lwas responsible,”
如果我出手…
“the one on the receiving end,”
那趴在桌子上的
would have been her husband!
应该是她老公
Each of you is so unique.
我听出来了 你们都个个身怀绝技
I've been betrayed.
有人骗了我
By who?
谁呀 谁呀
Tang!
老汤
How could he overlook the obvious?
这么明显的事 一个师爷看不出来
Huang is behind this scam.
这明明是黄四郎狗狼养的找人冒充的
Tang's not behaving properly.
他今天很反常
He must be up to something.
心里一定有和鬼
Who have you been seeing lately?
你最近跟什么人吃过饭
Master Huang?!
见过黄四郎
Don't move! Raise your legs.
不许动 举起腿来
Who's there?
谁
"A boy, my child!”
孩子 孩子
Your child?!
孩子
"Yes, mine.”
我的
You're a child?
你是个孩子
How old are you
几风
Eight!
八风
Come out!
出来
He's eight?
这是八岁
I find it hard to believe myself!
没人信 我都不信
As tall as Mom when he was three.
三岁跟他妈一样高
Taller than me when he was five...
五岁就跟我一样高 八岁就这样了
Screw youl!
你妈 你妈
"Mom, mom!"
妈 妈
Hands off my boy!
敢打傣娃
". Screw youl - Screw you, too!”
你妈 你妈
Screw youl!
你妈
"Yes, she is.”
是我妈
None of your goddamned business.
我家的事关你屁事啊 你妈
Stop it!
你妈
"Ma'am, what's going on?”
嫂子 怎么回事
I come for money. I won't leave until he pays.
我是来要钱的 不给钱我不走
He owes you?
不给钱不走
It was eight years ago in Shanxi.
这个老骗子 八年前在俺山西开矿
This crook made me pregnant.
骗了钱我就不说了 还骗了我的身子
He is a man of poor repute.
还不讲信誉
"Ran up a mountain of debts,”
他欠一屁股帐
then vanished without trace.
拍屁股走了
Creditors kidnapped my younger son.
人家问俺追帐 把我六岁的娃给绑了
He'll die if l don't clear his debts.
当人质呢 不给钱就斯票了
He's not my child
那不是我的
He is!
那就是你的
- He isn't. - He is!
不是我的 就是你的
He is! ] counted the days!
是你的 我算着日子呢
He swindled someone.
他骗了人家钱
"His victims tracked you down,”
人家到你那去要帐
and kidnapped your younger son.
把你的小儿子绑架了 绑架了
Threatening death...
不给钱就据票
"Yes, sol need the money.”
据票 所以我要钱呢
Pay her.
给钱
Money! The stones...
钱 石头
"Just a small gift, to mark our acquaintance.”
嫂子 初次见面 不成敬意
I don't want these. I want real money.
石头我不要 不给钱我不走
You stupid idiot...
你个傻…
These diamonds are worth a fortune!
这比钱值钱 这是宝石
No kidding?
子 真的
Bicycle!
自行车
I can ride that?
这就能骑
We rode one once in Shanghai.
我们在上海骑过
You have been to Shanghai?
你们俩去过上海
I'm sure you'd fall over.
不信 骑上准倒
Hop on!
上来
Let's gol!
走走了
Bicycle!
自行车
made of flesh and bones...
可是 肉的自行车
Havel come to the wrong place?
我来错地方了
Or at the wrong time?
我来的不是时候
Serve your customers,
接客
They're my customers.
他们俩都是
We're here first.
我们可是先来的
Have they paid?
付钱了吗
"The "bicycle ride" doesn't count.”
自行车能算钱吗
Show them out.
送客
But I've paid my dues.
上次我给过你很多钱
With what?
什么钱
Money you received through the window?
窗户外边扔进来的银子
Isn't that bandit money?
那不是麻菲扔进来的吗
l wonder if they are also bandits.
难道他们俩是麻菲
"No, they work for the Governor.”
他们不是麻菲 他们是官府的人
How dare you pay their tab with bandit money? !
你敢拿麻菲的钱给他们付帐
Cut the crap! Let her go!
别废话 先把人放了 快点
White knights to the rescue!
英雄救美
I'm no damsel in distress.
就算他们是英雄 我也不是美人
They're no knights in shining armour.
就算我是美人 他们也不是英雄
“After all, they're customers.”
老爷 毕竟他们是客人
I've already settled their bills.
今天晚上的钱 我蔡他们付了
"You taught me yourself,”
您不是常教育我们吗
customers are always supreme
客人永远是上帝
Isn't that right?
您说对吗
Yes!
对
“Instead of knights coming to your rescue,”
这就不是英雄救美了
they are being saved by a damsel.
是美救英雄
You're turning into a Mata Hari.
你呀 快成小凤仙儿了
You've just pissed him off.
你得罪他了
He doesn't need to be pissed off.
黄四郎不用得罪
“If he wants you dead,”
他想让谁死
I should've put a bullet through his head.
我刚才于嘛不一枪打死他呢
That would be the end of it.
我一枪打死他不就完了么
Don't be silly.
别傻了
Chief wants to go after his fortune.
大哥说了 留着他是要和弄他的钱
“If you're here for the money, then...”
既然想弄钱 那…
why are you giving it away?
你们干嘛到处发钱啊
Is this the right colour?
这颜色行么
Lower the umbrella.
把企拿了
The red is fine. Come over here!
红倒是够了 你…你过来
“First apply green, then red.”
先是绿 再弄红
". Okay, got it. - Understand?”
明白 明白这意思吧
Don't forget to lock up.
你把那锁好啊
- Bring the shovels. - Got it.
带上铁铂 知道了
- Six shovels! - Got it.7
六把铁铁 知道了
"Chief, how do llook?"
大哥你看我…
Hair is fine. Face is flushed. Come here...
头不用梳了 脸够红 你过来
Apply that to a dead man's face
死人的脸是绿的 加上点别的色
will turn it into pinkish red.
然后再变成这种红
- Got it. - Good.
明白了 明白了吧
Green.
绿
Come here.
你过来
Green is the base colour.!
绿在底下
Add that and you'll get this!
加上那个再变成这个就对了
". Oh, lsee... - Got it?”
明白了 明白吗
You want shovels like these?
是这样的铁欠吗
Shorten them and put them in the bag.
句短 装包里
How short?
多短
Short enough for the bag.
能装包里
Okay.
装包里
Hurry up! Six shovels!
快去啊 六把啊
Where are you going?
去哪啊这是
What's with the make-up?
怎么还扮上了
Are you leaving for good?
不是要跑吧
Come with us to give out money?
你去不去 我们去发钱
"No, what a waste!”
糟践东西 不去
- So you're not coming? - No.
不去是吧 不去
Now listen.
那我告诉你
"This time, may come back,”
我这次去 可能回得来
“but, then again, I may not.”
也可能回不来
"If ldo, you can leave with us.”
我要是回来 你就跟我跑
“If not, you plan your own getaway.”
我要是回不来 你就自己跑
Aren't you just giving out money?
去.…….去哪啊 不是发钱吗
"Yes, we are.”
是发钱
“at midnight tonight,”
半夜的时候
someone may come calling.
可能有人来找你
Engage him in conversation.
他要找你聊什么
"Whatever the topics,”
你就跟他聊什么
just chat along with him.
他怎么聊 你就怎么聊
"you have to stay calm,”
要慢 沉住气
make it nice and slow.
越慢越好
You saw it with your own eyes?
你亲眼看见的
Indeed.
我亲眼看见的
You saw the Governor leading his men out?
你亲眼看见县长亲自带队出发
"Yes, with my own eyes.”
我亲眼看见了
They've gone to give out money?
你亲眼看见县长亲自带队出发去发钱
Which mask does he wear?
他戴的是几简
“Mine
九简
Splendid. Tonight we shall only kill!
好极了 今晚不抢钱 杀人
"The Governor, wearing "Nine!"
戴九简的县长
"Masked or not, consider this done!" !
杀县长不用戴面具 您等着验尸吧
“All of you, put on your masks!"
回来 全给我戴上
"Firefight with bandits,”
麻菲火拼
“intrepid Governor killed!"
县长暴死
That would be music to my ears!
听着多么顺丁
Which mask is their leader wearing?
看清楚了 他们领头的戴几简
“Mine
九简
"Let's all change to ""four'™!"
全都换上四简
"Kill anyone who is not a "four!"
四简是自己人 其他人全打死
Which mask is their leader wearing?
那边领头的戴的是几简 看见了吗
BOUL
四简
"Know what we'll be wearing, then?”
那咱们应该戴几简 你知道吗
Got it.
明白
"Let's get rid of ""Nine™'!"
先弄死九简 走
"Master Huang, what brings you here?”
黄老爷 你怎么在这啊
Can I not visit the magistracy?
县衙我不能来吗
Light it!
点上
"When the cat prowls, the mouse seizes control!”
你们玩空城计 我就趁虚而入
Sit down!
坐
Where's the Governor?
县长呢
"Everyone is a "Four? I'm confused!"
都是四简 下不了手啊
"Tm confused, too!”
下不了手
It's bad to stay out in a thunderstorm.
打雷天站在十里头有点不讲究
"Yes, it's awful.”
太不讲究
Let's reschedule. Split!
那改天再约 撤吧
Be in touch!
撤
What now?
怎么撤
It's back to square one.
从哪儿来 回桂儿去鹃
"Yes, square one.”
好 从酵儿来 回哪儿去
"Split! 1, 2, 3."
一二三 撤
Listen! Someone's been shot.
听 枪一响 就有人死
Soon someone will mourn.
有人死 就有人哭
Mourning will lead to confessions.
人一哭 就要说心里话
Confess!
说吧
You've at least three confessions to make.
你至少有三句要说
I shouldn't have given your diamonds away.
我不该拿你的钻石送人
Try again.
不是这名
"l suggested "to kill someone, first destroy his soul.”
杀人诛心是我说的
Not that either.
也不是这名
We should have hosted the banquet instead.
鸿门宴要是我们请就好了
The banquet?.
鸿门宴 老爷
I can't hear you.
听不见
There was a shoot-out.
城里麻菲火拼
Six killed. We're unscathed.
死了六个人 咱们的人安然无羔
"Counselor, come take a look.”
师爷 来来 请
Your saviour may be among them.
或许…是你的恩人呐
"No, you are my saviour.”
您才是我的恩人
"If that is the case,”
既然我是你的恩人
"remove his mask,”
那就听恩人的话 揭开看看
and have a good look.
去吧 看看
"Come on, lights!"
来 照上照上
What's going on?
什么情况
What's happening here?
什么情况 什么情况
It's Hu Wan!
胡万
Hu Wan?
胡..….胡万
How come it's Hu Wan?
怎么会是胡万
This is weird!
怪了
“All those wearing ""four"""
四简啊
are my men!
全是黄家的人
Where are the bandits?
麻菲呢
Hu Wan was a bandit!
胡万 就是麻菲
He was one of them!
麻菲 就是胡万
"Murderers and kidnappers,”
杀县长夫人 绑架豪绅
“those who terrorised Goose Town,”
祸害鹅城百姓
were led by your own Hu Wan!
就是你黄老爷家的胡万
I wondered why you didn't fund the expedition.
我说你为什么不出钱划匪
You may even be the bandit chief himself!
原来你是贼喊捉贼啊
You dare to turn your guns on me?
你拿枪指着我
Do you want a shoot-out
你想跟我火拼
Take a good look at a bandit's fate!
你们看到了没有 这是当麻菲的下场
if he was my father...
死有余训
sooner or later!
早晚
You just shot Hu Wan 5 more times.
麻匪胡万又让黄老爷枪毙了五回
You want to show justice?
大义灭亲
Or to make sure he's dead?
杀人灭口
"Only "Pocky" Zhang would want to silence him.”
杀人灭口 你就是麻菲的头子张麻子
"If you'd only wanted to show justice,”
要是大义灭亲 那好办
why not fund my expedition instead.
你出钱 我荐匪
Done deal!
好啊
You shall receive a nice surprise in 3 days.
三天之后 一定给县长一个惊喜
He was Hu Wan's boss.
汤师爷 他是胡万的恩人
"Now he's your boss, too.”
现在又成了你的恩人
Please act as our interpreter.
你给翻译翻译
"What is a "nice surprise?”
什么叫惊喜
Interpret for me
翻译翻译 什么叫惊喜
There's nothing to interpret
这还用翻译 都说了…
"What on earth is a nice surprise?”
我让你翻译给我听 什么叫惊喜
It is what it is.
不用翻译 就是惊喜员
"You just don't get it, do you?”
难道你听不懂什么叫惊喜
Go ahead and interpret. What is it
我就想让你翻译翻译 什么叫惊喜
Translate for me!
翻译出来给我听
"What is this "nice surprise""?"!
什么他妈的叫惊喜
"What is this goddamned " “nice surprise?”
什么他妈的叫他妈的惊喜
"What is this "nice surprise?”
什么他妈的叫惊喜啊
"It means that in 3 days,”
惊喜就是三天之后
"TH put up $1.8 million for your campaign,
我出一百八十万 给你们出城某菲
to fix my crippled leg!
接上我的腿
Is that clear?
明白了吗
"That's the "nice surprise!"
这就是惊喜呀
Interpret.
翻译翻译
"The nice surprise is that,”
惊喜就是三天之后
“he will give you $1.8 million in 3 days,”
给你一百八十万两银子 出城制菲
to fund an expedition to fix his broken leg!
接上他的腿
What a nice surprise!
大哥这个是惊喜啊
I'm willing to wait 3 days.
小弟我愿意等你三天 好
Master Huang.
黄老爷
"L adore my Counselor,”
汤师爷是我的至爱
I can't let you have him.
你可不能夺我所爱啊
Fair enough.
了然 了然
Six.
六子
We're almost there.
事已经办了九成了
"Say, 70% clone.”
算七成吧
I've asked Two to take off first.
现在我就派你二哥出城
He'll wait for us at Emerald Creek.
到青石岭去接应我们
I will keep my promise.
剩下的事 我会说到做到
Know what you have to do?
你明白了吧
Yes.
明白
"When $1.8 million is in hand,”
一百八十万两银子到手
I'll consider Six avenged.
我觉着小六子的人算是报了
I feel that...
我觉着啊
my wife's death is also avenged.
不光六子 夫人的优也算报了
"Saviour, you still want to kill Huang?”
你不会真跟黄四郎玩命吧 恩人呐
I'm not your saviour. Huang is.
我不是你恩人 黄四郎才是你恩人
You're my saviour. Not him.
你是恩人 他不是
Did you think I was lying dead back there?
你当时真的以为我死了
"No, of course not.”
没有 绝对没有
Sure?
没有
Never crossed my mind.
从没这么想过
I've to hand this to you.
你蚜我可真算服了你了
"Abracadabra, and Hu Wan magically appeared!"
狸猫变太子 嘎登变出一胡万来
But I really clidn't get it.
可是我有一事不明
"Those six bodies,”
六有具尸体
"such a distance, so little time,”
这么长的距离 那么短的时间
how did you move them so quickly?
还抹着红脸蛋 你们是怎么搬来的
Huang and I took the shortcut.
我跟黄四郎可是一路小跑过来的
You've to carry six bodies.
你们搬着六个人
How did you manage?
来不及呀
They weren't buried at the magistracy.
我为什么要把人埋在衙门里
The bodies were buried there all along.
我把人就埋在了那
lensure the standoff was at their burial site.
人埋在桂儿 事儿就出在桂儿
That's where I led Huang to.
事儿出在哪儿 黄四郎就得跟到酵儿
"I'm convinced you're "Pocky" Zhang.”
那你真是张麻子
Sit down.
坐
My name is Zhang
我姓张
I know that.
知道
Zhang Muzhi.
叫牧之
A fine name!
好名字
It has auspicious meanings.
兖州牧 物州牧
You father must have high hopes.
牧之 令尊是望子成大器
“After graduating from military academy,”
从讲武堂出来
l enlisted in General Cai's army.
我追随过松坡将军
Served as captain of his riflemen.
给他做过手枪队长
How old were you then?
那年你多大
Seventeen.
十七
A youthful genius!
少年得志啊
"Cai was wounded during the Battle of Luzhou,”
后来泸州会战 将军负了伤
and later died in exile in Japan.
再后来 将军死在了日本
I came back alone.
我回来了
The country was in total chaos.
正磁上军闪混战 天下大乱
Sol became a bandit.
我只得浪迹江湖 落草为寇
"They nicknamed me "Pocky."
牧之也被叫成了麻子
Shame! You're so handsome.
可惜啊 多好的一个牧字
"People have an odd way of thinking,”
人们不愿意相信
that bandits shouldn't have proper names.
一个土匪的名字叫牧之
"They love calling their bandits ""Pocky"".”
人们更愿意相信他叫麻子
"Not only that,”
人们特别愿意相信
they want their bandits scarred and scary.
他的脸上应该长着麻子
People can be so ignorant.
这人可真够驴蛋的
"[ too was a tenderly 17,”
那年我也十七风
and so was she.
她也十七风
"Stop, I'm not interested.”
停 我不愿意听你的故事
I don't confess to just anyone
我一般不跟人说心里话
I've to continue now that I started.
这都到嘴边了 你不能让我咽回去吧
Take it back!
咽回去吧
It's all made up anyway.
因为你说出来也是假的
You're a conman!
你是个骗子
"In our part of China,”
北国我不知道
there are only two such landmines.
在我南国 这样的珍藏版地雷
Both limited edition.
只有两颗
Made in U.S.A. - 1910!
美国制造 一九一零
Bang and everything's in smithereens!
了 一响 它就没了
"So if it doesn't take some lives with it,”
所以 不带走几条人命
it'd be such a waste.
那就是卑鄙的浪费
Well...
那么…
where's the other one?
另外一颗地雷呢
It exploded.
炸了
The first bang during the 1911 Revolution!
辛亥革命的第一响
"Oh yes, I've heard!
我知道了
It went off at Xinhail!
炸在辛交这个地方了
Xinhai's not a place! It's a revolutionary icon!
辛亥不是个地方 是一种革命
You should've said so earlier.
您要早这么说我就了然了
"Now, tell me about this one.”
那还是说说这颗吧
You must stay focused.
谁让你问那颗的
"Lwant it to shake the world,”
所以 它要炸得惊天
Understood.
了然
"Pick a good spot,”
选个好地方
find an auspicious time...
选个好时辰
"So, who's our target?”
那么.…炸谁
You should've asked...
你应该问…
™ Where?"
炸在旦
Where the expedition force must pass.
其匪的路上
Yet another expedition?
这么快又要某菲了
Canhave a bigger cut this time?
那这回我能多分点吧
You can have it all if you're the real Pocky!
你要是真的张麻子 钱都给你
"No problem, sir. I'ma fake.
了然 我是假麻子
I'll take whatever you can spare.
老爷给我多少那是对我的恩赐
When do you want it to blow up?
那么 什么时候炸
That's our denouement
什么时候炸那是第三步
Let's play out our second act slowly.
且让我把第二步慢慢走好
Hold still!
都别动
Let her speak.
让好说
Two left without saying goodbye.
老二不辞而别
Now Three is leaving too.
老三又要走了
You are tearing us apart!
我们活活的被你们拆散了
You're doing this for Two or Three?
女侠 你是为了老二还是为老三员
Shut up!
闭嘴
"I know your left hand's intention,”
你左手的意思我懂
I know your right hand's intention.
右手的意思我也懂
But both hands together... don't get it.
两只手这么待着 我看不懂
I'd rather be dead!
要么成 要么死
Typical Scorpian!
AB型
Shut up!
闭嘴
"Sit down, all of you.”
你们都坐下
Let me talk to her.
我再跟她聊聊
You were bought by Huang?
你是被黄四郎买来的
Yes.
对
Been mistreated?
他打过你吗
Have I ever laid hands on you?
我打过你么
No.
没有
- Hate him? - Yes.
你恨他吗 恨
-And me? -No.
恨我吗 不恨
Then why threaten me with a gun?
那你不拿枪指着他 你拿枪指着我
Because you're a good person.
因为你是好人
What?
什么
What kind of stupid logic is that?
这是什么狗屁道理
You threaten me because I'm good?
好人就得让人拿枪指着
"Flora, Chief is right!"
花姐 大哥说得对
Go back! Sit down!
回来 坐下
You bunch of idiots!
你们这群王八蛋
I told you to give money to the poor.
我让你们把钱发给穷人
And you gave it to her?
你们发给一个女人
I warned you but nobody listened.
我说什么来着 没人听啊
Shut up! You're a born cheat!
闭嘴 天生的老骗子
Always plotting to swindle me.
时时刻刻想骗我
Working with Huang behind my back.
跟黄四郎勾勾搭拱
"When a bandit confronts a godfather,”
一个土匪磁见一个恶霸
the outcome should be simple.
多么简单的事
How can you screw up so badly?
让你们给弄成这么烂七八糟的
How dare you still point your gun at me?
你还敢拿枪指着我
“If l don't dare to draw a gun on you,”
不敢拿枪 当不了麻匪
I'll never make a good bandit.
我敢拿枪指着你
I dare you all!
我胆儿大吧
Whose quirky idea is this?
你们谁给她出的这个主意
Whose?
谁
Il was just teasing her
我就是跟她说着玩的
"Yes, to give money out to the poor,”
对呀 我想跟你们一块儿发钱
to hear and share their joy.
把钱袋子扔到窗户里 听他们笑
You're now one of us.
你现在就是了
But lam not prepared.
我还没准备好呢
No need!
不用准备
Did you make preparation?
你们都准备过吗
No.
没有
How about you?
你准备过吗
I was eating hotpot and singing songs.
没有啊 我吃着火锅唱着歌
My train plunged andl ended up here.
扑通一下掉水里 出来就到这儿了
We're leaving Goose Town soon.
我们要离开忽城
But you have to stay.
你就留在忽城
No.
不
A bandit must have discipline.
当麻菲要听命令
Chief is right
大哥说得对
"But she has a point, too.”
刚才说的也对
lI have an important mission for you.
我有个很重要的事交给你
Ithink you can manage.
我看你挺合适
A nice surprise indeed. !
果然是个惊喜
He is not Ma!
果然他不姓马
"Now that we know,"
有了这个惊喜
my next move can be more leisurely.
我的第二步就能走的更加悠然
Leisurely?
悠然
Impersonating a governor warrants capital punishment.
盗官欺避 放在前清
His whole clan dies with him!
满门抄斩
"Master, just you wait.”
老爷 你等着
lll go and blow him away!
我这就一枪贿了他
No!
不
"Before they die,”
他们死以前
I want to toy with these circus monkeys.
我还要好好地要要这两只猴
"But Master,”
我的老爷
they're not worth your while.
这两只猴子不值得您页
"No, [must toy with them!”
要要 一定要要
"Otherwise, I couldn't get others to pay,”
不要猴 我怎么赚到两大家族的钱
“the Governor couldn't go and fight the bandits,”
不要猴 他们怎么心甘情愿地去荐菲
and they wouldn't trot on my landmine!
不某菲 他们怎么能踩到地雷呢
Huang has a double.
黄四郎有个替身
They are indistinguishable.
跟他长得一模一样
I can't tell if this is really Huang.
我和弄不清楚这个是黄四郎 还是他的替身
Ineed you to check for me.
你帮我去看看
He's a fake.
假的
He's not Huang.
他不是黄四郎
Told you I'm not Huang!
我已经跟你们说过我不是他
lreally am not him
我真的不是他
I'm certain.
肯定不是
Let me go.
放了我吧 放了我
Keep an eye on him until our return
那好 你帮有我们看住他
“If you have to, use your guns.”
等我们回来 就用你手里的枪
I've never used a gun.
我不会用枪
"Three, show her how."
老三 你教教她
Is that your photo?
这照片是你吗
"Yes, it's mine.
是我
Sure?
是吗
"Yes,"
电 下
I was slimmer then.
那时候我还很瘦
I don't think it's you.
这就不是你
Itisn't?
你说他不是我
"No, it isn't.”
不是
I don't think so either.
我说他也不是我
"No, that ain't me.”
这根本就不是我
What is this all about?
那到底是怎么回事
I was totally baffled myself.
我还想知道是怎么回事
"When I bought the post, l needed papers.
花钱买了个县官 我总得有个证件吧
"had my picture taken at a gallery,”
我去照相馆照相 取照片的时候
and that's what they gave me.
他们给我的就是这张
I said the man in the photo wasn't me.
我说这不是我 他们说这就是你
They insisted that it was.
我说他不是我 他们说这就是你
I've no choice but to use it.
没办法 我就把它贴在这了
Bullshit!
政什么呀
That's obviously me!
这明明是我
lam the real Ma Bangde.
我才是马邦德
Iwas ambushed by bandits on my way here.
是这样 我进城以前遇见麻菲
He saved! my life.
幸亏有他 才躲过一友
So I let him take the post.
我一想 索性让他假扮县长
“After all, he’s my nephew.”
毕竟是自家外曙嘛
"Uncle, we shouldn't be telling him this.”
三筋 这话能跟他说吗
Shut up!
闭嘴
"I've travelled all over China,”
黄老爷见笑 马某走南冯北
Ihave been governor in 9 counties.
在九个地方做过县长
l excel in confusing facts with fiction!
靠的就是以假乱走、鱼目混珠之章法
"So, Governor Ma...”
那么…马县长…
Yes?
你说
He's addressing me.
叫我呐
"Just as l uncover the truth,”
我刚措清你们的底细
you blow your own cover!
你们就不打自招
What a coincidence.
太巧了吧
™" Stop frowning to dispel ill feelings,
有道是: 展颜消宿急
“and brush aside quarrels with a smile."
一笑泥恩做啊
Want to make peace?
你想跟我和解
Splendid. Where's my double?
好啊 我的替身呢
Return him and we'll call it quits.
还给我 前面的账一笔勾销
We've killed him.
撕票了
Which asshole ordered his execution?
于个王八蛋让你撕票的
You're that asshole!
你个王八蛋让我撕票的
I dare you to pull your trigger!
开枪 你开枪我也能先打死你
Lay down your guns!
放下
I know I could take you out first.
开枪 你先开枪 我也能先打死你
Put down your guns on my count of three!
把枪放下 我数三下
"One, two, three!"
一 一
“Huang, put it down!”
老黄 你先放下
"He may be a brute, but you too?”
他不懂事儿 你也不懂事啊
You're the worst!
你最不懂事
When are you leaving for your expedition?
你们什么时候出城荐菲
We aren't.
走不了
We can't leave without funding.
钱不到手 出不了城
We can't fight without leaving!
出不了城 荐不了菲
You've failed to live up to your promise.
黄老爷 您说话不算数啊
You had agreed to
鸿门误上说得好
lead the contribution
你带头出钱
in order to make the others pay.
再套出两大家族的钱来
"Not only have you not put up any money,”
可是你不但不出钱
you've also fought us posing as bandits!
还扮成廊菲跟我们打来打去 不仗义啊
Wrong! You saw my men dressed up as bandits.
错 你们看见的廉菲 是我扮的
"I saw yours posing as bandits, too.”
我看见的麻菲 是你们扮的
"But when the others see these bandits,"
可是他们看见的麻匪
they wouldn't know that they're fakes.
他们以为是真的
Now is the time to pay for the expedition.
现在正是让他们出钱某匪的好时机
“If l pay, others will follow suit.”
只要我出钱 他们一定会出
Where's your money?
你的钱呢
It's all here.
早已经为你准备好了
I've money stowed away everywhere!
忽城到处都是我的钱
It's all here?
都在这儿
This is only half of my share.
这只是一半
Each family will have to put up the same.
我们想赚多少 他们必须出多少
"Uncle, this is a trap.”
三时 有诈
Atrap?
诈
"After all these confrontations,”
来回这么多趟 死了这么多人
he has not put up a dime.
他一分钱都不出
Why so generous all of a sudden?
今天怎么突然出了这么多钱
"Yes, you did.”
太突然了
Want to know why?
想知道吗
Governor!
县长
You?
你
I won't make a Governor?
我做不了县长
Don't I look the part?
我不像个县长
"Yes, you can swear in as soon as we leave.
像 我们一走 你就上任忽城
Goose Town?
忽城
I bought governorship of 6 more counties!
我买了六个县的县长
I can't handle all on my own!
我一个人当不过来
Get out!
出去
Leave us.
退下
I need you to govern three of them for me.
老马 你来帮有我当三个县的县长
Brilliant! I'm good at governing.
好啊 这事我拿手
"Hey, wait...”
等会
"What about me, then?”
那.….那我干什么呀
You...
你嘛…
“can play “Pocky” Zhang!"
来当一个假的张麻子
Great ideal!
好啊
"Since the abdication of the last Emperor,”
自宣统皇帝退位以后
Goose Town has 51 governors.
忽城一共来过51任县长
"They're all bastards, parasites and leeches!"
他们都是王八蛋、禽兽、畜生、寡生虫
"But our beloved Governor Ma,”
但是这位马邦德县长
“is neither a bastard, parasite,”
他不是王八蛋 不是畜生
"leech, nor a beast!"
不是禽兽 也不是寄生虫
He risks his life to combat the bandits.
他今天亲自带队 出兵某菲
He is our hero!
他是我们的大英雄
"Counselor, please.”
师爷 请
It's time for heroes to take centre stage!
大风起兮云飞扬
It's time for heroes to show their mettle!
安得猛士今走四方
We must rid ourselves of these bandits.
麻菲 任何时候都要基
We don't have a choice.
不划不行
“Imagine, if you take your wife out,”
你们想想 你带着老婆
“singing, eating hot pot and be merry,”
出了城 吃着火锅 还唱着歌
"Llong for a world without thieves,”
所以 没有麻菲的日子
for days of wine and roses!
才是好日子
"Governor, please!
县长 请
March!
出发
"Saviour,"
恩人
want to check this out?
给你看个宝贝
Isn't that the warrant?
这不就是委任状嘛
Ma Bangde is hereby appointed...
兹委任马邦德.怎么了
Read on!
后面
8th month of the 8th year of the Republic...
中华民国八年八月…
Don't miss out the words in between...
念你没念过的字 当中
Ma Bangde is hereby appointed Kang County governor...
兹委任马邦德为康城县长…
Kang County?
康城
Not Goose Town?
不是牧城吗
It has always been Kang County.
从来就是康城
You bastard!
好小子
Blame yourself!
外你啊
"When you dumped me in the river,”
你把我泡水里 九简扣脸上
“scared as l was, [had an inspired moment.
闹钟味哮哮响 吓死我了
I brought you to Goose Town.
我灵机一动 让你去忽城
What's their difference?
这忽城和康城有什么不一样啊
Kang County is affluent. Goose Town is deadly.
康城富饶 忽城凶险
Why Goose Town for me?
那你为什么让我去啊
"You're a tough cookie, aren't you?”
你鬼扯鹃 截火车
There can only be two outcomes.
我告诉你啊 你进了忽城就有两种情况
“Either Huang kills you dead,”
第一 你进城就被黄四郎弄死
and I'll move on to Kang County.
我马走康城 从容上任
"Or we sort out Huang instead,”
第二 你有种 咱俩办了黄四郎
like what's happening now.
就像现在这样
Very clever!
好 说得好 马邦德
You goddamned crook!
你这个骗子
"One day Pocky will get you, and blast you to hell!”
早晚有一天 你会被张麻子一枪骨了
You won't. You love me too much,
你崩了我 你舍不得
"You still think I'm "Pocky Zhang?”
你还真相信我就是张麻子
"If not, the real one must be somewhere around.”
你要不是张麻子 这山上可就有真麻子
We're doomed if we run into him!
张麻子一来 你我可就没命了
Speak of the devil!
张麻子 …
Tell our men to hold their fire!
告诉弟兄们 散开
Scatter! Run for the peak.
别开枪 往山项上跑
10 to the west.
西边十个
§ to the south.
南面六个
Another group to the east.
东边还有一大片
Tell Seven to join Three!
让老七去找老三
Secure our west flank.
先把西边的收拾掉
Message from Three. West is secured.
老三来信 西边搞定
These pheasant calls really work wonder!
这鸡叫成电台了 我看行
Tell them!
告诉他们
Three joins Four to secure our south.
让老三去找老四 把南边于掉
Seven back to protect the Counselor.
老七回来保护师爷
Three and Four are done.
大哥 老三老四他们得手了
I'm back. I'm back.
大哥我到了 大哥我到了
Stay with the Counselor!
师爷交给你了 快
Understood.
明白
"Counselor, come!”
师爷 快
Three!
三哥
It looks like Two.
好像是二哥
Pocky Zhang is here.
南国张麻子在此
Leave your money...
钱留下 银子也留下…
It's Two.
昌 一 Er 正一可
Is he dead
死了吧
Goddamned it!
我弄死你妈的呀
Tell everyone to go east.
告诉弟兄们 上东边去
Bring one in for interrogation.
抓着活的 问出他们头在酵
lll kill their leader myself.
我亲手宰了他
Let's move.
上东边
Where's your leader?
头在哪儿
"In the north, with a pockmarked face.”
北面 验上有麻子的就是
Go north! On the hill.
北面 山顶上
AmI dead?
我没死吧
"No, you're still alive.”
没有 没死
Do you want to signal a message?
没死 要说什么 我帮你吹
How do you whistle?
怎么吹 怎么吹
Can you lead the way?
你带我走吧
"No, [can't run any more.”
不.…跑不动 …
"Follow me, then.”
我带你走
Ican't run.
跑不动…
You've only blown up your cheeks.
不是嘴坏了吗
Your legs are fine.
嘴坏了用脚跑啊
The Chief is dead?
大哥死了
You just signalled the Chief's death!
你把大哥给吹死了
“Five, go check it out.”
老五 你去看看
Chief!
大哥
They said you're dead.
他们说你死了
Bullshit! Am [not alive?
放他妈的屁 我这不还活着吗
"Why missed out signalling "bullshit?"
放他妈的屁怎么没吹啊
Hear that?
听见没
He said we're full of shit.
骂咱们放你娘的屁呢
Wait.
等会儿
They caught the fake!
假麻子抓到了
"You're "Pocky Zhang?”
你是张麻子
Where are your pockmarks?
你脸上怎么没有麻子呢
No one asking that question has survived.
这事谁问谁死
Oops! I take it back.
明白了 不问了
I've got something special.
我这儿有一宝贝
"You can have them,”
送给你了
in exchange for nvy life.
能换我一条命吧
What happened to them?
那…那两个人呢
“If I tell you, will you spare me?”
说实话能换一条命吧
Speak!
快说
I sawed the legs off the tall one.
大个的被我给锯了 比矮个的还矮
And the short one?
矮的呢
She died of fright at the sight!
当场就被吓死了
Counselor.
师爷
Counselor..
师爷 师爷
Who's behind this scam?
谁让你冒充我的
Master Huang.
黄老爷
Nice pockmarks!
麻子哪儿来的
He burnt them.
他汤的
How many governors have you robbed?
劫了几任县官
Will you spare me?
说出来能换条命吗
Speak!
快说
"I've killed five governors,”
五回 五个县长全被我给干掉了
and shared the loot with Master Huang.
钱我跟黄老爷给分了
What's that?
那是什么
A governor's silver umbrella.
万民企 那五个被我于掉的县长留下的
Take it!
全都给你
- Which way to Shanxi? - I have four more.
山西往哪边走啊 我还有四把呢
I know the way.
我知道
Will you spare me if I tell you?
说出来能换条人命吧
Goddamned it! Speak!
快他妈说
Come back! You mustn't go that way!
哎呀 不能往东 千万不能往东
But Shanxi really is to our east.
山西确实是在东边
"Are you really "Pocky Zhang?”
你到底是不是张麻子
"Yes, lam.”
我是
"Lam about to kick the bucket,”
我可是快要死的人了
don't lie to me.
别骗我
Don't worry.
放心
"Lreally am Pocky’ Zhang.”
我就是张麻子
Pocky!
麻子
Yes?
哎
it hurts.
屁股疼
Counselor.
师爷
Your ass is on that tree.
屁股在树上呢
You can't feel it.
不疼了
"On my ass over there,”
我树上的屁股
[have another five warrants.
的口袋里有五张委任状
Take them.
都给你
Promise never to return to Goose Town.
听我的 于万别回鹅城
You can't beat Huang.
你呀 弄不过黄四郎
Take the money and run.
带上银子 走吧
"Don't worry, l won't go back.”
你放心 我不回忽城
lied about two other things.
其实 我还有两档子事儿骗过你
No big deal.
骗了就骗了吧
No.
不行
I must confess before I die.
我死之前 我必须告诉你
"What was the first lie, then?"
你说 头一档子
Can I confess my second lie first?
我.…我能说这第二档子事儿吗
Yes.
好
Do you still remember...
那谁…你还记得吗
I can't quite figure you out.
我弄不清楚
Counselor Tang or Governor Ma?
你到底是老汤 还是马邦德
"Now that you're gone,”
但是你没了
™ Pocky” Zhang, too, is no more. "
张麻子也没了
Fact or fiction no longer matter now.
真的也没了 假的也没了
"For you, I'll go back and finish this war!"
兄弟 我要帮你把这个县长当下去
Brothers!
弟兄们
March on Goose Town
回忽城
"This "Pocky" Zhang”
这个张麻子
has killed his imposter.
杀了假麻子
"But instead of fleeing with the money,”
得了钱 不逃命
he wants a showdown with me.
莫非要跟我鱼死网破
Let's get reinforcement.
那就请官兵来荐匪
I've sent Hu Bai to fetch troops.
我早就派胡百过去了
Cavalry will arrive in 3 days.
三天之后郭旅长的骑兵就到了
"Governor swears to behead Huang,
县长要斩黄四郎
public enemy number one.
谁人不想斩黄郎
"Trades in opium and human misery,”
拐卖壮丁贩烟土
Huang has killed five governors.
杀了五任好县长
"The money that's been given out,”
一成白银送你手
is but one-tenth of his hoard!
九成真金黄家藏
"In memory of his cleacdl comrades,”
邦德发拆三天内
Ma will parade Huang’s head in 3 days!
除暴安良祭老汤 除暴安良祭老汤
He gave away all his money to the poor.
白花花的银子都散给了穷人
Disgraceful!
作人敬
The money is not being taken!
老爷 散不了吧
No one dare to go hear except those geese!
你瞧 除了外 没有活物敢过去
lll go and find Flora!
我去找花姐
Bring her and Huang’s double back.
你把花姐和替身都给我找回来
We only have three clays.
三天之内必须找回来
What is on his mind?
这个张麻子到底要于嘛呢
They're a bunch of clowns!
他们于什么都是白于
We simply want them... dead!
咱们一个字 斩
"He has sworn publicly,”
可他说过
to behead me in 3 days.
三天之后斩我人头
Some said I'd win the lottery too!
判辆当年还说要斩秦始皇呢
Can the four of us
大哥 三天
kill Huang in three days?
就我们四个要杀黄四郎
Yes.
对
We've been telling everyone that.
还把话说出去了
We can't back out now!
话不说出去 事就办不成
What are our chances?
胜算有几成啊
30%? Are we out of our mind?
三成不是玩命吗
Time for a nap. Keep watch.
我去睡会儿琳 你们在这上采着
Queen!
南风
Knavel
北风
Bingo!
胡叶
"Chief, the money is gone.”
大哥 银子都没了
I could see that.
我看见了
We must have a 40% chance now!
现在有四成了吧
50%?
五成
70%?
七成
Surely not!
不能吧
Still only 30% after they took the money?
老百姓把钱都拿回家了 还三成啊
“If things are that simple,”
银子要是这么被拿走了
our efforts will be in vain.
那钱就白发了
Send the carriages!
出车
"TIL show you how to” “borrow arrows with a straw boat!"
我要你看一看 什么叫做草船借稍
"But we just sent horses, hot straw boats.”
老爷 咱们放的是马 不是船
Idiot!
你这个傻瓜
It's only a metaphor!
这叫比喻 比喻 …
You're almost metaphysical!
不就是赤壁嘛
Huang has taken all the silvers.
银子都被黄四郎收走了
We've no chance of winning.
胜算都不到一成了
"Huang didn't even have to show up,”
黄四郎都没出面啊
everyone has surrendered their money.
老百姓把所有钱都交出去了
How can it be 60%?
于来六啊
Well said! So why 60%?
说得对 为什么
It's because of fear.
怕啊
What lies beneath fear?
怕里边有什么
Rage!
有怒
We need to bring forth their rage!
我一定把他们心里的怒给勾出来
“As guns and ammos wait for you,”
满街枪弹在你手
Huang hoards fortune in his citadel.
十成白银在确楼
I like that!
我喜欢
Those are guns! Send carriages?
那是枪啊 要不 放马
Money incites greed. But guns are seditious!
拿银子 是贪 拿枪 是反
They wouldn't dare.
他们没这个胆
The money's gone, but the guns remain!”
银子被收走了 枪也没人拿
hat do we do now?
怎么办 大哥
What are our chances?
胜算几成
Huang has taken all the money.
黄四郎把所有的钱都给收了
But no one takes our guns.
我们发的枪也没人拿
How come it's 70%?
吾来的七成啊
“If he hadn't taken the money, I wouldn't have to distribute the guns!"
黄四郎要是不收银子 我发枪于什么
. wouldn't have distributed the guns!
黄四郎不收银子 我发枪干什么
heed a nap.
去睡会儿
- Queen! - Bingo!
东风
I got it!
南风 胡了
You were inciting rage and anger!
我明白了
Collect the guns.
你发的不是枪 你发的就是怒
You missed?
收枪
Let the bullets fly!
没动静啊
Shots were fired!
让子弹飞一会儿
Look!
枪响了
They're all raging mad!
看 她了 全都怒了
How dare they shot my horse?
他妈的的刁民 敢杀我的马
Those with guns follow me.
枪在手 跟我走
Kill Huang
杀四郎
and storm his citadel.
抢确楼
Kill Huang and storm his citadel...
杀四郎 抢奋楼 …
Those with guns follow me.
枪在手 跟我走
"Chief, look.”
大哥 大哥你看
Only they have come this far with us!
跟我们来的只有它们
We're on our own!
高兴早了 没人帮咱们
I see.
明白了
They will only side with the victors.
谁赢 他们帮谁
We can't overcome Huang's 400 men!
黄四郎四百人 我们四个人 怎么赢啊
Shoot! We can win!
打 打就能赢
What's our target? There's only a gate.
打酵儿 这只有铁门
"Let's blast the gate, then.”
就打铁门
How many people have they brought?
他们鼓动了多少人
Just the four of them.
就他们四个
You're kidding!
不可能吧
fifty geese.
五十只忽
Great! Let them shoot!
打 打够
Let them goddamned shoot!
让他打个够
It's almost day break.
大哥 天快亮了
If Three doesn’t return in time...
三哥不回来可就.…
I know what's on your mind.
我知道你是怎么想的
Can you draw an exclamation mark?
知道惊叹号吧
Let's do one on the gate!
在门上打出个惊叹号来
Right on.
好嘲
What's that? Where's the dot?
这像惊叹号吗 那点呢
You missed!
焉了
Move over.
躲开
A hook stroke?
色
Look again!
再看
A question mark!
问号
“If you can shoot straight,”
小子 你只要打得准
you'll have nothing to worry!
什么时候都能跑
Empty your guns
把你们的子弹
at the question mark!!
从那问号的点里打过去
Okay!
好叱 快
"Chief, chief..."
大哥.…
Speak up!
说 说话
I'm back!
我回来了
"Three cays,”
三天整
Where are they?
人了呢
They're here.
都在那 走
"You're back, at last.”
你可回来了
I'm not Huang! I'm just an actor!
我不是他 我只是个唱戏的
What happened?
怎么回事
He ran away and I chased after him.
他跑我就追 他跑我就追
We ran a long way!
就越跑越远了
He finally succumbed after I'd him cornered.
他跑我就堵 就给堵回来了
That was it?
就这么简单
"Yes, that simple.”
对 就这么简单
Brothers!
弟兄们
"To mark Three's return,”
为了庆贺三哥回来
let's go and empty our guns!
把所有的子弹都打出去
- Right. - Let's go!
好 走
What about me?
那我呢
Squat!
趴下
Just four of them?
就他们四个人
Go and take a look.
去看看
Someone will die!
要出人命图
There will be fatalities!
要出人命了
At least one of them will die!
至少得死一个
Hoist!
起
Brothers! We've won the war!
弟兄们 我们打赢了 凯旋
Understood?
明白吗
Understood!
明白
Say it out loud!
说一遍
"Yes, victory.”
赢了 凯旋
Follow me.
跟我走
Huang's been captured.
黄四郎被抓了
Kill!
杀
"Shit, we're in trouble!"
糟了 糟了
I've died as my double!
我成替身了
Reclaim what's yours from the citadel!
去确楼 拿回你们自己的东西
Come with me!
跟我来
Charge!
杀
The citadel’s been breached?
再楼打进去了
Yes!
对
Huang's been captured!
黄四郎被抓住了
They took him for his double.
正被当成替身 挨捷呢
You've ended Huang's reign.
黄四郎的威风是被你砍了
What do we do with him now?
他这肉身怎么办啊
Let him go?
留不留啊
"You bastard, go over here! Over there!”
欠打的过来 过去
Stand properly!
站好了
My fellow townsfolk!
乡亲们
Huang has died!
黄四郎是死了
But he has got off lightly!
但死得太便宜了
Swoosh!
哮嘛
He was fell in one blow
被那个思春县长
by that stupid Governor!
一刀给砍了
That was stupid! That was ignorant!
何止是思春 简直就是思春
That's not justice!
这公平吗
No! It's not!
不公平
Can you let this pass?
乡亲们答应吗
No!
不答应
lam not him.
我不是他
I know you're his double.
我知道你是蔡身
But you shared his life and committed his crimes.
替他享福 替他作恶
So you should be punished
你就应该蔡他 把他没受过的罪
as if you were him! Kneel down!
给我受够了 跪下
really am not him!
我真的不是他
Kneel down! Kneel!
跪下 跪下 …
Don't make me mad!
别让我发脾气
On my count of three!
我数三下
One!
一
What the...? Who's the son-of-a-bitch?
谁 哪个欠打的
Want your ass kicked again?
又想反板子了是吧
"AmI bothering you, sir?”
大人 我讨厌吗
Say the word and I'll disappear.
如果我讨厌 我立马消失
“If not, I'll just carry on.”
如果不讨厌 我继续欺负他
Go away.
很讨厌
"Right, we're going.”
大人 兄弟我就走了
Just yell if you need me.
需要兄弟的时候 你吃喝一声
"Always at your service, sir.”
兄弟立马出现
"Goodbye, sir. Beat it!”
告辞 告辞 走
What's next for you?
下一步有什么打算
Take my place here?
留在忽城代替我
I'm not a caged bird.
我不是家禽
You're a predator.
你是野兽
"The day of your inauguration,”
进城那天 如果我亲自去接你
“had greeted you in person,”
不是叫胡万过去给你捣乱
would things have turned out differently?
结果会不会不一样
It was a nice hat. I liked it.
那帽子挺好 我喜欢
[have nicer ones at home.
那不是最好的 我家里还有更好的
I can give them to you.
转头送给你 行
Everything's gone in a flash.
一下子弄成了这样
You've totally wiped me out.
你让我输得很惨啊
It's not that bad.
惨吗? 黄老爷
"You're still having a smoke,”
你现在还抽着烟
still chit-chatting.
还说着话
"But Six, Two, Counselor and his wife...”
可是六子、老二、师爷、夫人
I can no longer hear their voice.
我听不到他们的声音了
Never ever again.
而且永远听不到了
"Their four lives,"
你们四个人
“in exchange for my heirloom,”
换我五代家业
isn't that enough?
不合算吗
That's none of my business.
怎么算帐那是你的事
"To me,"
对我来说…
They are separate issues.
钱是钱 人是人
You could have kept the money.
钱归了你 我认了
But why did you give it away?
为什么要散给他们
"Master Huang, let me ask you a question.”
黄老爷 我问你个问题
Shoot!
说
Which is more important to me?
你说是钱对我重要
You or your fortune?
还是你对我重要
Me.
我
Think again.
再想想
Can it be the money?
不会是钱吧
Neither matters to me.
你和钱对我都不重要
Then what is?
那谁重要
To rid of you is more important.
没有你 对我很重要
Looking for a light?
你不是找火柴吧
No.
不是
You must be...
那…
looking for this.
你是找这个
You're a man of honour.
你是个体面人
There's only one bullet left.
只有一颗子弹
That's enough.
够
Wait.
等等
Any message for Tang?
有话要我带给老汤
"Right, tell him...”
对了告诉他…
lowe him an apology.
我对不起他
Hied to him.
我骗了他
What was your lie?
你骗了他什么
I said wouldn't come back.
我跟他说我不回鹅城了
But here lam.
可是我回来了
You should have kept your promise.
你应该说到做到
"Yes, Llet him down."
是啊 所以我对不起他
"But when it comes to you,”
可是我对你
I'll definitely keep my words.
就要说到做到
Understood.
明白
Governor...
县长 县长…
These chairs are mine.
这两把椅子归我了
Easy...
别慌 怎么了
Canlask you a question?
我能问你个问题吗
Sure.
说
"You fancy Flora, right?”
你喜欢花姐对吗
"Governor,"
县长 县长
may l interrupt?
我觉得我可以出现了
l overheard everything.
刚才我都听见了
Huang is not an honourable man.
他可不是个体面的人
I gave hima pistol.
我给了他一把手枪
He can take his own life.
他要是体面 你就让他体面
"If he doesn't, lend him a hand.”
他要是不体面 你就帮他体面
Understood.
我明白
lI have 9 ways to skin this cat!
我有九种办法弄死他
Nine ways!
九种
You'll hear my roar!
听我的雷声
Maybe just a little. Why?
是有这么回事 怎么了
Don't say I tipped you off.
于万别说是我说的
"Chief, we're off to Shanghai.”
大哥 我们准备去上海了
Not riding back with me?
不跟我回山里了
Still want to resume banditry
还想回山里啊
You're too old for this.
您这腿脚都不利落了
You should've given me a heads-up.
怎么也不跟我打个招呼
That's what we're doing!
这不正要跟您打招呼了嘛
Didn't you want to be one of us?
你不是要跟我当廉菲 到处发钱吗
just helped to dish out the money.
今天不是把钱都发光了吗
I've never had a more satisfying cay!!
还有比今天更过交的
I'm even dressed for the part!
你看我都穿上这身了
So...
这么说…
you've changed your mind?
你改主意了
That goes without saying!
那还用说吗
"What's your plan, Three?”
老三 你有什么打算
"I'm going to marry her, on behalf of Two.”
我要替二哥娶她
Two...
老二咽老二….
"Chief, I'm Three!”
大哥 我是老三
"Three, it no longer thrills you”
老三 你跟我在一起
to ride with me?
不高兴吗
it's been hard going lately.
有点不轻松
What about you?
你们俩呢
We've had...
有点
better days.
不轻松
Seven?
老七呢
“Flora,”
姑娘
“hold your guns like this,”
你这么拿着枪
makes you look even cooler.
更好看
They're yours.
送你了
"Chief, we've got to go.”
大哥 那我们先走一步啊
"Goodbye, Chief.”
走了 大哥
Gol
走
Give me a heads-up next time.
别忘了下回跟我打个招呼啊
"Chief, take care.”
好 保重大哥
Take care.
保重
"Goodbye, Chief!”
大哥再见
"Rocky" Zhang!"
张麻子
"Six, Two, Counselor, Madam...”
老六 老二 师爷 夫人
Did you see that?
你们看到了吧
"Three, Shanghai or Pudong?”
老三 去上海还是浦东
"Three, Pudong or Shanghai?”
老三 去浦东还是上海
Shanghai is Pudong!
上海就是浦东
Pudong is Shanghai!
浦东就是上海